<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Careers on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/</link><description>Recent content in Careers on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:15:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Analyst Intern</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/data-analyst-intern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:15:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/data-analyst-intern/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA is looking for a Data Analyst Intern for a 3-month position to support the ongoing development of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, a WhatsApp-based AI service that delivers personalised, science-backed advice to farmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtual Agronomist has seen explosive growth in 2025, with advice given on over 280,000 farm plots in Africa. The intern will guarantee high quality of incoming farm data and offer technical assistance to the operations teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This internship will be suitable for any candidate with a technology or data analysis background. You will be leveraging your analytical skills to make a real-world positive impact on smallholder farmer livelihoods. This is the real world of live, messy data and will require attention to detail, problem-solving and communication!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software Development Intern</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/software-developer-intern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:15:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/software-developer-intern/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA is &lt;strong>seeking a Software Development Intern for a 3-month position&lt;/strong> to support the ongoing development of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, a WhatsApp-based AI service that delivers personalised, science-backed advice to farmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtual Agronomist has seen explosive growth in 2025, with advice given on over 280,000 farm plots.
The intern will collaborate with our software development team to design, build, test, and deploy new features for Virtual Agronomist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This role is ideal for early career candidates with a background in computer science or software development and a strong interest in &lt;strong>conversational AI and improving agriculture&lt;/strong>. The internship offers a unique opportunity to work at the intersection of &lt;strong>software engineering, decision science, machine learning, agronomy,&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>AI-driven user experiences&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Non-Executive Director</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/board/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/careers/board/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA is redefining what’s possible in African agriculture.
We’re the organisation behind Virtual Agronomist - Africa’s fastest-growing AI-powered
advisory platform - built to boost the incomes and resilience of millions of small-scale
farmers. With science at our core and scale as our goal, we’re delivering expert, hyperlocal
advice to farmers across the continent - at a fraction of the cost of traditional extension
services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since launching Virtual Agronomist in 2024, we’ve reached over 250,000 farmers across
multiple countries - with proven impact on yields and profitability. Our diverse and ambitious
team operates across Africa and Europe, and we’re just getting started.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>