<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/</link><description>Recent content on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developer Portal</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-do-i-sign-up-to-use-the-isdasoil-api"&gt;How do I sign up to use the iSDAsoil API?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up by creating a username and password on our &lt;a href="https://isda-africa.com/api/registration"&gt;sign up page&lt;/a&gt;. This
will be required to obtain an access token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-can-i-do-with-the-isdasoil-api"&gt;What can I do with the iSDAsoil API?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our API will allow you to retrieve soil property and agronomy information for any location within Africa (excluding
water bodies and deserts) by providing values for latitude and longitude. Most of our layers are at 30m resolution,
except those provided by third parties. For further details on the available data, see our FAQ.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Technical Information</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/technical-information/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/technical-information/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-were-these-maps-made"&gt;How were these maps made?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope it will give you a good understanding of the unique process we’ve developed to create our maps. For detailed information on our workflow, please read our paper in &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-85639-y"&gt;Nature Scientific Reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our key output is spatial predictions of crucial soil nutrients and properties, based on the predictive soil mapping (PSM) techniques. The first step in this process is to standardise all the input soil data by i) ensuring all measured units are in the same format; ii) harmonizing properties measured using different techniques; and iii) removing any erroneous datapoints.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil on the AWS Registry of Open Data</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/isdasoil-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/isdasoil-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This page contains information about how to access the &lt;a href="https://registry.opendata.aws/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil data hosted on the AWS Registry of Open Data&lt;/a&gt;, as well as background information about the dataset that will help you to use it. To visually explore the maps that we’ve created, please visit the &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil homepage&lt;/a&gt;. You can find more detailed information on how the maps were made on our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/technical-information"&gt;technical information&lt;/a&gt; and further information on our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/faq"&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="data-overview"&gt;Data Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data has been prepared as cloud-optimised geoTIFFs (essentially geographically aware images). A single file covers the whole of Africa. Related data have been grouped together as bands in a single file. For most soil property predictions, this means that each file has 4 bands – the predicted mean value, and model error (expressed as 1 standard deviation) at 2 soil depths: 0-20cm and 20-50cm. For covariate data the number of bands is variable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Supporting Healthy Soils for Healthy Cities: Virtual Agronomist's Role in Urban and Peri-Urban Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 marks the United Nations World Soil Day (WSD). This year&amp;rsquo;s theme, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Healthy soils for healthy cities,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; highlights the critical role of soils in urban areas. Healthy urban soils filter water, store carbon, regulate temperatures, support biodiversity and even sustain food production. With two-thirds of the world&amp;rsquo;s population expected to live in cities by 2050, there is an urgent need for a one health approach across urban spaces to sustain and restore the health of our soils, the health of our cities, ecosystems and people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA's Chief Scientist Dr. Keith Shepherd Wins 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rabat, Morocco – November 19, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; – iSDA is proud to announce that Dr. Keith Shepherd, Chief Scientist, has been awarded the 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award. The award was presented yesterday during the IFA Strategic Forum in Rabat, Morocco, recognizing Dr. Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s contributions to plant nutrition research and sustainable agricultural development across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-testament-to-scientific-excellence-and-real-world-impact"&gt;A Testament to Scientific Excellence and Real-World Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shepherd was selected by the Scientific Panel on Responsible Plant Nutrition (SPRPN). The panel was particularly impressed by the clarity of achievements from his research, which spans from significant scientific innovation to large-scale, tangible impact on the ground, delivering solutions that directly benefit smallholder farmers across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA at COP30: Bringing Africa's Climate-Ready Farmers to the Global Stage</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="belém-brazil--november-12-14-2025"&gt;Belém, Brazil | November 12-14, 2025&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in our history, Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (iSDA) took our place at COP30, the world&amp;rsquo;s most important climate conference. As delegates from nearly 200 countries gathered in Belém, Brazil, at the very edge of the Amazon rainforest, we delivered a powerful message: building climate resilience for Africa&amp;rsquo;s smallholder farmers isn&amp;rsquo;t a future promise. It needs to happen now, at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>COP 30</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/cop-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/cop-30/</guid><description>&lt;section&gt;
 &lt;div class="container py-10 d-flex flex-column justify-content-center" style="min-height: 50vh;"&gt;
 
 &lt;div class="row text-center mb-8"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12"&gt;
 &lt;h1 class="display-3 fw-bold mb-0 text-primary"&gt;1.6x Yields, Stronger Resilience: See How AI is Solving Africa&amp;#39;s Soil Crisis.&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 

 &lt;div class="row align-items-center"&gt;
 
 &lt;div class="col-12 order-md-1" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;

 
 

 
 

 
 &lt;div class="fs-lg text-muted mb-6"&gt;
 Join &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bruce-kisitu-05459530" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Bruce Kisitu&lt;/a&gt;, our Director of Operations, Africa at iSDA&amp;rsquo;s major global climate stage debut as he presents &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; role in building climate resilience for African smallholder farmers.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;section data-jarallax data-speed=".8" class="py-10 jarallax text-white"
 style="background-image: url(/img/virtual_agronomist/DSC_8457%20copy_hu_a99412c634f4a0c9.jpg); min-height: 100vh; background-size: cover; background-position: center;"&gt;
 &lt;div class="container d-flex flex-column justify-content-center" style="min-height: 100vh;" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center justify-content-start"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6" style="background: #565b6ceb" &gt;
 &lt;h1 class="display-3 fw-bold mb-0 mt-6 text-success"&gt;The challenge&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center justify-content-start"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6" style="background: #565b6ceb"&gt;

 
 

 
 &lt;h2 class="mt-3"&gt;
 
 &lt;/h2&gt;

 
 &lt;div class="fs-lg mb-6"&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt; of African soils are degraded, undermining food security and climate stability across the continent. Climate resilience must be built from the ground up. The technology exists. The results are proven. The time for action is now.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;





 






 
 




&lt;section&gt;
 &lt;div class="container py-10 d-flex flex-column justify-content-center" style="min-height: 50vh;"&gt;
 
 &lt;div class="row text-center mb-8"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12"&gt;
 &lt;h1 class="display-3 fw-bold mb-0 text-primary"&gt;The Breakthrough&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 

 &lt;div class="row align-items-center"&gt;
 
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-5 col-lg-6 order-md-1" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;

 

 
 
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/charts/2025%20activity_hu_471232508944e972.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/charts/2025%20activity_hu_59d14ade7664ff09.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/charts/2025%20activity_hu_471232508944e972.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid rounded shadow-lg"&gt;

 
 

 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-md-1" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;

 
 

 
 
 &lt;h2&gt;
 From Pilot to Powerhouse: 250,000 Farmers in One Year
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 

 
 &lt;div class="fs-lg text-muted mb-6"&gt;
 Discover how iSDA&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Agronomist transforms complex agronomic data into clear, actionable advice, tailored to each farmer, each plot, each season. This is precision support at scale, proving that soil resilience and climate action can be achieved together for real-world impact.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;section data-jarallax data-speed=".8" class="py-10 jarallax text-white"
 style="background-image: url(/img/virtual_agronomist/DSC_8566%20copy_hu_35fe12799558aca6.jpg); min-height: 100vh; background-size: cover; background-position: center;"&gt;
 &lt;div class="container d-flex flex-column justify-content-center" style="min-height: 100vh;" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center justify-content-end"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6" style="background: #565b6ceb" &gt;
 &lt;h1 class="display-3 fw-bold mb-0 mt-6 text-success"&gt;The conversation&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center justify-content-end"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6" style="background: #565b6ceb"&gt;

 
 

 
 &lt;h2 class="mt-3"&gt;
 
 &lt;/h2&gt;

 
 &lt;div class="fs-lg mb-6"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;See how AI-driven soil health is creating a new model for climate adaptation, one that&amp;rsquo;s affordable, scalable, and already working across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Changing the Yield Curve: How Smarter, AI-Powered Advice Can Transform African Farming</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/changing-the-yield-curve/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:09:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/changing-the-yield-curve/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Africa’s smallholder farmers have produced only a fraction of the yields seen elsewhere. Despite billions spent on seeds and fertiliser, productivity has stagnated - not for lack of effort, but because most farmers lack access to one thing the rest of the world takes for granted: field-specific agronomic advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That advice works. Traditional agricultural extension, where agronomists visit farms in person, can double or even triple yields - but it typically costs $30–60 per farmer per year, a figure that makes continental coverage impossible. iSDA has found a cheaper way. Our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; uses artificial intelligence to deliver site-specific recommendations through a simple chat interface for about $1 per farmer per season. Already serving more than 250,000 farmers, it has achieved yield increases of up to 60 per cent. If those results scale, Africa’s next agricultural revolution could be digital rather than mechanical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Product Manager’s Perspective on the Future of African Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/manuel-exec-profile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 10:07:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/manuel-exec-profile/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A Product Manager’s Perspective on the Future of African Agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI and agronomy are powerful forces in transforming smallholder agriculture. But without strong product leadership, the benefits can remain out of reach for farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, &lt;strong&gt;Emmanuel Gyampo&lt;/strong&gt; plays that connecting role. As Product Manager for &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, he brings together agronomists, data scientists and farmers — helping translate complex models into simple, actionable advice farmers can trust. In this interview, Emmanuel shares how he bridges these worlds to make data-driven farming work on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From 250,000 to 500,000: What We’re Learning as Virtual Agronomist Scales</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/from-250000-to-500000/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:47:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/from-250000-to-500000/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2024, we launched &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; with a bold question: &lt;em&gt;what if every farmer
could have a personalised, season-long advisory service in their pocket - no matter where they live, what they grow, or how much land they have?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just over a year and a half later, more than 250,000 smallholder farmers across seven
African countries have used Virtual Agronomist to register and manage over 350,000 plots.
And in the year ahead, we are on track to reach half a million farmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>“I Can Now Do Agri-Business the Right Way”: Farmers Turning Virtual Agronomist Advice Into Income</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/advice-into-income/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:30:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/advice-into-income/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Smallholder farmers are the backbone of African agriculture, producing over 80% of the continent’s food.
Yet despite their hard work, many struggle to earn a decent income. Poor soils, expensive
fertilisers and limited access to expert advice mean that effort doesn’t always translate into profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; is changing that. Our science-backed, AI-powered advisory tool delivers
personalised, expert guidance via WhatsApp, helping farmers not just grow more, but earn more.
Already in use by over &lt;strong&gt;250,000 farmers across 350,000+ farm plots&lt;/strong&gt;, Virtual Agronomist is turning
subsistence into scale — boosting yields (by &lt;strong&gt;1.6x&lt;/strong&gt; on average), increasing incomes and creating opportunities
for long-term investment. And it’s doing so at a &lt;strong&gt;tenth of the cost&lt;/strong&gt; of traditional extension.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A month of momentum for Virtual Agronomist and a look ahead to COP30</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/month-of-momentum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:01:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/month-of-momentum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Bruce Kisitu, Director of Operations, Africa.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past month has been one of the most energising periods I’ve experienced in my time with iSDA. In the space of just a few weeks we had the privilege of engaging with some of the most important conversations shaping the future of African agriculture, while also witnessing the ever-growing tangible impact of our work on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Africa Food Systems Forum in Dakar, the energy in meeting rooms, panel discussions and exhibition halls was palpable. The urgency around food security, resilience and inclusive growth could not have been clearer. iSDA was proud to contribute a science-driven, tech perspective, demonstrating that scalable digital solutions are not a distant possibility - they are happening today. Our AI-advisory tool, Virtual Agronomist, has already been adopted by over 250,000 smallholder farmers, and, in recent weeks we have been seeing an extraordinary surge of around 4,000 new registrations every single day! These numbers are not just statistics - they represent households making more informed decisions, fields being managed with greater precision and harvests that have a better chance of withstanding climate uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What Agronomists Can Teach AI — An Interview with Dr. Paul Chunga</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/paul-chunga-interview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:22:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/paul-chunga-interview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence is often hailed as the future of farming. But without real agronomy - the science of crops, soils and farming systems - AI is just numbers. At iSDA, agronomists like Dr. Paul Chunga are making sure that Virtual Agronomist doesn’t just crunch data, but delivers advice that actually works for farmers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Malawian agronomist with nearly a decade in CGIAR institutions, a PhD in agronomy and applied plant physiology, and now Senior Agronomist at iSDA, Dr. Chunga has dedicated his career to bridging science and practice. We spoke to him about his journey, and why agronomists are essential to shaping AI in agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One Youth Farmer, 15,000 Others Inspired</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/amos-spotlight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:48:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/amos-spotlight/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, digital agriculture is reshaping how young people see farming. Drones, climate apps, mobile advisory platforms are making agriculture look cool, profitable and modern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s working: the majority of digital agriculture users in Africa are aged 15–35, showing how technology is pulling a new generation back to farming. From Hello Tractor in Nigeria to DigiFarm in Kenya, young people are driving adoption. Projects like Hinga Weze in Rwanda and startups like M-Omulimisa in Uganda are proving the same thing: give youth the right tools, and they transform agriculture into a business worth staying in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Reaches 250,000 Farmers: Scaling Real Solutions, Fast</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/250000-unique-farmers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:38:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/250000-unique-farmers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just one month ago, we announced that Virtual Agronomist had reached more than 250,000 farm plots with locally tailored, AI-powered advice. Today, that figure already looks out of date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve now passed 350,000 farm plots, and for the first time, we can say we are directly serving a quarter of a million farmers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more than a milestone. It’s evidence of huge, rapid growth — and of the power of a model that is working at scale, and in reality, for African farmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Last Mile, First Priority: What It Takes to Get Tech to the Field</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/last-mile-first-priority-monalisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 13:04:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/last-mile-first-priority-monalisa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Q&amp;amp;A with Monalisa Mutesi, iSDA’s Uganda Country Director&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The last mile is where change takes root. If you care about scale, you have to get your hands dirty and your boots muddy.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monalisa Mutesi is the driving force behind iSDA’s work in Uganda — and a firm believer that the best agtech means nothing if it doesn’t work for farmers on the ground. As Uganda Country Director, she leads iSDA’s last-mile delivery work: connecting science to farmers, turning insights into impact and building partnerships that make scale real.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beyond the Harvest: How Virtual Agronomist Is Doing More Than Improving Yields</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/doing-more-than-improving-yields/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:04:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/doing-more-than-improving-yields/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Last year’s income was quite high, so I decided to build a good house for me to live in, and this is what I am working on finalising.”&lt;/em&gt;
— Dorcas Macharia, smallholder farmer, Reru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, smallholder farmers face mounting challenges - unpredictable weather, rising input costs and limited access to expert guidance.
But change is underway, driven by a new generation of science-backed tools like iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-virtual-agronomist-works"&gt;How Virtual Agronomist Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Agronomist delivers personalised, expert advice via WhatsApp, tailored to each farmer’s soil,
crop and weather conditions. It guides decisions on fertiliser use, pest control and planting schedules - combining local data with cutting-edge science.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What If Every Farmer Could Diagnose Their Soil? Now They Can</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/know-your-soil-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 10:10:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/know-your-soil-release/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Despite extensive scientific effort in creating soil maps, they seldom reach farmers in a usable form.
Know Your Soil changes that by delivering tailored summaries of soil constraints for each field, together with clear, actionable management recommendations.
Farmers are also guided through simple on-farm observations to identify more subtle issues - such as structural limitations - and adapt their practices accordingly.
Accessible via WhatsApp through Virtual Agronomist, Know Your Soil serves as a practical learning resource for both farmers and extension agents.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Advice in Action: Virtual Agronomist Delivers Higher Yields for Ugandan Sunflower Farmers</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/uganda-sunflower-farmers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:33:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/uganda-sunflower-farmers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Uganda’s agricultural sector plays a vital role in driving economic growth, reducing poverty and ensuring national food security.
Contributing around 24% to GDP and employing over 70% of the population, agriculture is the country’s economic backbone.
Yet with most farming rain-fed and subsistence-based, the sector remains highly vulnerable to climate change - especially to increasingly frequent and severe droughts.
By 2050, climate impacts are projected to cause economic losses of up to US$1.5 billion for smallholder farmers across Africa. Their livelihoods - and national food systems - are under growing threat.
That’s why iSDA is building tools that combine world-class science with cutting-edge technology to help farmers adapt.
At the centre of this work is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist (VA)&lt;/a&gt; - our AI-powered advisory tool, delivered via WhatsApp, that provides data-driven,
hyper-local advice to farmers across Africa. What makes VA different is its foundation in science: it generates fertiliser and nutrient management plans tailored to individual plots,
using high-resolution soil data from &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s most detailed soil mapping platform. By pairing soil diagnostics with real-time insights on pests, disease and weather,
Virtual Agronomist helps farmers make smarter decisions - boosting productivity and building resilience to climate shocks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Science Still Matters in the Ai Era</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-science-still-matters-in-the-ai-era/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 11:30:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-science-still-matters-in-the-ai-era/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a world increasingly focused on artificial intelligence and digital solutions, Dr. Keith Shepherd has always been driven by one fundamental question: how can science truly serve farmers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As iSDA’s Chief Scientist, Keith has spent decades building the tools and data systems that underpin modern agricultural decision-making in Africa. From co-leading the Africa Soil Information Service to pioneering the use of infrared spectroscopy for rapid, low-cost soil analysis, Keith’s work laid the foundation for iSDAsoil – Africa’s first high-resolution map of soil properties – now widely used by researchers, governments and farmers alike. But for Keith, data is only powerful when it leads to action.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why the Next Generation of Farm Advisory Needs More Than Just Cool Tech</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-the-next-generation-of-farm-advisory-needs-more-than-just-cool-tech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:58:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-the-next-generation-of-farm-advisory-needs-more-than-just-cool-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, millions of farmers face a fundamental challenge: they lack access to timely, tailored advice that can help them make confident decisions about their crops and soils.
This isn’t a new problem. What’s new is the tools at our disposal to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we believe the future of farm advisory is more than just tech. It’s about trust, science, systems - and scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-more-tech-doesnt-automatically-mean-better-advice"&gt;1. More Tech Doesn’t Automatically Mean Better Advice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, we’ve seen a surge in AI-powered platforms promising to revolutionise smallholder agriculture. And yes - technology is unlocking new possibilities. But when tech is deployed without a deep understanding of agronomy, local context or farmer realities, it risks repeating old mistakes in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building Virtual Agronomist: Notes from a Kenyan Software Engineer</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/notes-from-a-kenyan-software-engineer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 11:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/notes-from-a-kenyan-software-engineer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Meet Abi Wairimu, one of the brilliant minds behind Virtual Agronomist. Her
journey began with a passion for computer science and a belief that technology could
transform African agriculture and has led her to playing an instrumental part in
bringing Virtual Agronomist to life. Here she shares how combining AI, science and
farmer insights has created a tool that’s as much about people as it is about tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-first-drew-you-to-this-work"&gt;What first drew you to this work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started studying computer science, I was fascinated by the potential of
AI systems and how they could be applied to solve real-world problems. So when I had
the chance to help build Virtual Agronomist, I jumped at it. It brings together
machine learning, expert systems and generative AI - but what excites me most is
that it’s already delivering tangible value to farmers across Africa.
This isn’t just a lab experiment - it’s AI at work in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shaping the Future of Agriculture with AI and the Gates Foundation</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-the-gates-foundation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 18:48:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-the-gates-foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/ideas/articles/next-chapter"&gt;recent article&lt;/a&gt;, Bill Gates reaffirmed the Gates Foundation’s commitment to driving progress through artificial intelligence, noting, &lt;em&gt;“We’ll continue supporting new uses of artificial intelligence, which can accelerate the quality and reach of services from health to education to agriculture.”&lt;/em&gt; At iSDA, we are proud to be part of this vision, actively contributing to the Foundation’s mission to harness AI for inclusive transformative development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through platforms like our Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service and iSDAsoil, we are demonstrating how AI can deliver tailored, actionable insights to boost productivity, improve resilience, and enhance livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>API Registration</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/api/registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:30:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/api/registration/</guid><description/></item><item><title>200,000 Plots and Counting: Celebrating One Year of Our Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory Service</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In its first year, our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has provided tailored nutrient recommendations for over 200,000 farm plots across Africa. This confirms our mission to empower African farmers with easy-to-access tailored, data-driven insights to enhance productivity, profitability, sustainability, and decision-making. Using our extensive knowledge base, &lt;a href="isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; soil analysis, and advisory engine, our service is designed to provide instant, personalised guidance throughout the farming season — helping farmers optimise crop health, manage resources efficiently, and navigate climate challenges with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA and KPLUSS Partner to Bring Cutting-Edge Agronomic Advisory to Farmers in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-kpluss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 11:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-kpluss/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we believe that knowledge is the most powerful tool a farmer can have. That is why we are excited to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.kpluss.com/en-us/"&gt;KPLUSS Fertilizers Kenya Ltd.&lt;/a&gt;, a collaboration set to revolutionise how farmers access agronomic advice and optimise their fertiliser applications for better yields and higher profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this partnership, we will introduce our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; to farmers within the KPLUSS network, providing them with expert guidance on the best agronomic practices in a way that is both scalable and financially sustainable. This year, we hope to reach 1,000 farmers growing rice, coffee, beans, sorghum, and potatoes across the Kirinyaga and Meru counties in Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>17 Crops Now Supported by AI Virtual Agronomist Across All African Countries</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/17-crops-for-all-countries-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 10:47:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/17-crops-for-all-countries-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Smallholder farmers across Africa can now access tailored advisory services for 17 different crops through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI platform&lt;/a&gt;, reflecting the growing demand from those who have already benefited from the system. With over 100,000 farmers using our service, many have experienced its value and are eager to extend its benefits to more crops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, our team has continuously expanded the crop offerings to better support farmers’ diverse needs. These updates to our service enable farmers, agribusinesses, and organisations to receive personalised, location-specific recommendations to enhance yields, increase profits and improve soil health across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Progress Update: Our Growing Partnership with Niger Foods</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/niger-foods-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/niger-foods-update/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a step toward advancing agriculture in Nigeria, we have partnered with &lt;a href="https://nigerfoods.com"&gt;Niger Foods&lt;/a&gt; to deliver AI-powered advisory services to farmers in the Niger State. Through this collaboration, we deploy our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;, providing maize, soybean, and rice farmers with real-time, data-driven insights to optimise crop management, improve soil health, and increase yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having launched earlier this year, the initiative aims to support 10,000 farmers initially, expanding to 50,000 by the end of 2025. By leveraging technology to enhance productivity, this partnership is set to transform farming practices, improve profitability, and promote sustainability, creating a more resilient future for agriculture in Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Delivers 100,000 Tailored Advisories to African Smallholder Farmers in the First Year</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to share that iSDA’s &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has helped African farmers on over 100,000 plots - a fantastic milestone achieved in just one year since the launch of the AI expert advisory in February 2024! This achievement is more than a number - it is real impact. Thousands of farmers are now equipped with AI-powered, data-driven insights which helps them to instantaneously know their soil status (NPK values) and get a nutrient plan to adopt sustainable farming practices, improve their yields and increase their income.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Transforming Agriculture in Ghana: Our New Partnership with Sesi Technologies</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-sesi-technologies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 11:16:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-sesi-technologies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we are thrilled to announce our new collaborative partnership with &lt;a href="https://sesitechnologies.com"&gt;Sesi Technologies&lt;/a&gt; to bring our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; to farmers across Ghana. This initiative is more than a project – it is a shared vision for empowering smallholder farmers with the knowledge they need to improve their livelihoods through smarter, data-driven farming practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sesi Technologies provides technology solutions to help African farmers and agribusinesses to boost productivity, minimise losses and enhance their earnings. Since 2018, the company has delivered products and services that have positively impacted the lives of over 2,000 farmers and agribusinesses in Ghana and beyond, collaborating with the World Food Programme and other international partners to work to create a better life for farmers through innovative technology solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A New Chapter for Agriculture in Uganda: Our Partnership With Sasakawa Africa Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-sasakawa-africa-association/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:52:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-sasakawa-africa-association/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce our groundbreaking partnership with &lt;a href="https://saa-safe.org"&gt;Sasakawa Africa Association (SAA)&lt;/a&gt; in Uganda, a company who have been working alongside smallholder farmers since 1986. SAA partners closely with national agricultural extension services in Ethiopia, Mali, Nigeria, and Uganda to assist smallholder farmers throughout the agricultural value chain. Its mission is to enhance farmers’ incomes and improve food and nutrition security by promoting sustainable, regenerative, and nutrition-sensitive agricultural innovations while building the capacity of extension agents and farmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unveiling the Impact of iSDA's Rice Harvest Data Survey in Mwea, Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/unveiling-the-impact-of-isda-rice-harvest-data-survey-in-mwea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:16:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/unveiling-the-impact-of-isda-rice-harvest-data-survey-in-mwea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rice production is central to Mwea’s agricultural identity, contributing significantly to Kenya’s food security and economy while supporting thousands of smallholder farmers. However, challenges such as resource inefficiencies, soil degradation, and the need for precise farming practices make it difficult to meet growing demands sustainably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tackle these issues, our team at iSDA conducted a retrospective cohort study to assess the impact of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; compared with normal Farmer Practice in the Mwea Rice Scheme in Kenya. Designed to deliver tailored, data-driven recommendations, our Virtual Agronomist advisory service aims to enhance farming practices and boost productivity for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2024 in Review: Celebrating a Year of Milestones and Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2024 comes to an end, our team at iSDA are proud to look back on a year marked by progress, innovation, and meaningful impact. This year has been a significant step forward in our mission to transform smallholder farming across Africa through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;, empowering farmers with tailored, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From expanding our reach to enhancing the accuracy of our AI-driven advice, we have seen firsthand how Virtual Agronomist can support sustainable farming practices, improve yields, and unlock potential for communities that rely on agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist at the CPCN Seminar: Revolutionising Agronomic Advice for Farmers Across Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where smallholder farmers face increasing challenges in achieving sustainable productivity, technology has emerged as a powerful ally. At the recent CPCN seminar, our innovative &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; took center stage. This cutting-edge tool delivers personalised agronomic advice directly to farmers via WhatsApp, bridging the gap between scientific insights and on-the-ground farming practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net"&gt;Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition (CPCN)&lt;/a&gt; seminar is coordinated by Dr Canon Engoke, Senior Scientist at the &lt;a href="https://www.apni.net"&gt;African Plant Nutrition Institute&lt;/a&gt; based in Nairobi, Kenya. The CPCN serves as a dynamic platform where companies, research institutes, universities, NGOs, and national programs collaborate to share expertise and data. It fosters the co-creation of aligned crop nutrition principles, standards, algorithms, and other vital resources. The seminar provides a hub for innovation, aiming to accelerate the development of effective, evidence-based digital crop nutrition advisory solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Showcasing Virtual Agronomist at the 3rd African Conference on Precision Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/showcasing-virtual-agronomist-at-the-3rd-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:09:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/showcasing-virtual-agronomist-at-the-3rd-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We were thrilled to make a significant impact at the &lt;a href="https://paafrica.org"&gt;3rd African Conference of Precision Agriculture (AfCPA)&lt;/a&gt;, held in Marrakech, Morocco, from December 3rd to 5th, 2024. Representing iSDA, our Southern Africa agronomist, Paul Zauzau Chunga, delivered a presentation to showcase our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="highlighting-the-power-of-the-virtual-agronomist"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlighting the Power of the Virtual Agronomist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul’s presentation showcased the remarkable achievements of our Virtual Agronomist service, with a focus on its deployment for four key crops: sunflower and lowland rice in Tanzania, maize in Côte d’Ivoire and Uganda, and sorghum in Uganda. Backed by strong data, we demonstrated how the implementation of Virtual Agronomist significantly boosts agricultural productivity for small-holder farmers:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist Featured by Voice of America: Transforming Farming in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we are committed to revolutionising agriculture across Africa by empowering farmers with valuable agronomic knowledge. Our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual_agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory service&lt;/a&gt; is designed to equip farmers with actionable insights tailored to their unique needs. Recent testimonials from Mwea, Kenya, where rice farming thrives, reveal the profound impact of this technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mohammed Yusuf from &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com"&gt;Voice of America&lt;/a&gt; recently visited farmers in Mwea, including Henry Gichobi, who shared how Virtual Agronomist has transformed his approach to farming. By leveraging Virtual Agronomist’s AI-driven analysis, Henry now makes data-informed decisions about fertilisers and chemicals, resulting in a dramatic increase in yield. &amp;ldquo;Before this technology, I was harvesting less than 20 bags. Now, I harvest 26 bags and above,&amp;rdquo; he said. With precise satellite imagery and soil nutrient data, Henry receives recommendations that maximise his productivity while reducing unnecessary input costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Science</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/scienceandtech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 15:44:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/scienceandtech/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/impact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/impact/</guid><description>&lt;section&gt;
 &lt;div class="container py-10 d-flex flex-column justify-content-center" style="min-height: 50vh;"&gt;
 

 &lt;div class="row align-items-center"&gt;
 
 &lt;div class="col-12 order-md-1" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;

 
 

 
 

 
 &lt;div class="fs-lg text-muted mb-6"&gt;
 iSDA exists to transform smallholder farming – using science, data and partnerships to deliver high-quality advice at massive scale and low cost.
At the centre of this is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, our AI-powered platform that delivers customised, plot-level guidance to farmers
via WhatsApp – already used by over 250,000 farmers across seven African countries.
Here, we set out how we’ll achieve impact at scale – reaching millions of farmers, transforming national extension systems and unlocking a future of sustainable farming for all.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;section data-jarallax data-speed=".8" class="py-10 jarallax text-white"
 style="background-image: url(/img/virtual_agronomist/DSC_8457%20copy_hu_a99412c634f4a0c9.jpg); min-height: 100vh; background-size: cover; background-position: center;"&gt;
 &lt;div class="container d-flex flex-column justify-content-center" style="min-height: 100vh;" data-aos="fade-up"&gt;
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center justify-content-start"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6" style="background: #565b6ceb" &gt;
 &lt;h1 class="display-3 fw-bold mb-0 mt-6 text-success"&gt;What We Stand For&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center justify-content-start"&gt;
 &lt;div class="col-12 col-md-7 col-lg-6" style="background: #565b6ceb"&gt;

 
 

 
 &lt;h2 class="mt-3"&gt;
 
 &lt;/h2&gt;

 
 &lt;div class="fs-lg mb-6"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The AI Engine of African Agriculture.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re building the AI engine powering a resilient African agriculture – one that’s open, evidence-led and farmer-first.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building Better Futures: Our Partnership With OMMA Ltd.</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/building-better-futures-our-partnership-with-omma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/building-better-futures-our-partnership-with-omma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we pride ourselves on using cutting-edge agricultural technologies to empower farmers and improve livelihoods. It is with great enthusiasm that we announce our partnership with OMMA Ltd, a unique ecosystem that enhances food security, promotes sustainability, and stimulates economic growth, based in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collaboration marks a significant step forward in delivering precision agriculture tools directly to those who need them most: smallholder maize and rice farmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empowering Farmers in Uganda: Our New Partnership with Ecolife</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-announces-partnership-with-ecolife/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:26:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-announces-partnership-with-ecolife/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we believe that data-driven solutions can transform agriculture, especially when combined with local expertise and on-the-ground support. We are thrilled to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.ecolifefoods.org/"&gt;Ecolife&lt;/a&gt; in Kitula-Namayumba, Uganda, aimed at launching our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; for 1,000 maize farmers. This initiative, which began in September 2024, is focused on driving improved yield, quality, and profitability for local farmers while supporting Ecolife’s mission of sustainable agricultural growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA &amp; IAPRI Release Empowering Documentary</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-iapri-collaborate-for-documentary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-iapri-collaborate-for-documentary/</guid><description>&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oiQUzPH6ASE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="our-collaboration-with-iapri"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Collaboration with IAPRI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we’re excited to work alongside the Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute (IAPRI) to promote our innovative Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service. Initially, IAPRI used local media to reach farmers in the pilot districts of Kapiri-Mposhi and Monze in Zambia through community radio. However, as interest grew, they decided to scale the outreach to a national level. This led them to partner with the Zambian National Broadcasting Corporation (ZNBC) to create a documentary that highlights the benefits of Virtual Agronomist’s AI technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA Announces New Board Member: Mr Richard Sears</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/announcing-our-new-board-member-richard-sears/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:36:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/announcing-our-new-board-member-richard-sears/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the appointment of Mr Richard Sears to the iSDA Board of Directors. With a diverse career spanning across multiple sectors including technology, finance and non-profit work, Richard is an accomplished entrepreneur and investor. His extensive global experience covers regions such as Europe, Africa, Asia, and South America, where he has successfully launched multiple ventures, non-profits, and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="our-new-board-member"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our New Board Member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard currently serves as Investment Director at Kuvi Capital, where he leads venture and private equity investments, managing a portfolio of 25 companies across Europe, Africa, and the U.S. Prior to this, he played a key role as Head of Ventures at The Baobab Network, an accelerator supporting early-stage African tech companies. His work has empowered over 25 start-ups across 11 African countries, in partnership with global investors and corporations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA Africa Announces Exciting Partnership With Niger Foods</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-working-in-partnership-with-niger-foods-to-revolutionise-agriculture-with-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 15:16:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-working-in-partnership-with-niger-foods-to-revolutionise-agriculture-with-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a significant step towards transforming agriculture in Nigeria, we are excited to announce a groundbreaking partnership with &lt;a href="https://nigerfoods.com"&gt;Niger Foods&lt;/a&gt; to deliver AI-powered advisory services to farmers in the Niger State!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this partnership, we will deploy our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; to provide maize, soybean, and rice farmers with real-time, data-driven insights and advice to enhance crop management and increase yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our service will provide personalised recommendations for essential agricultural practices, including fertiliser application and pest control, tailored to the unique conditions of each farm and will assist the farmers in improving their soil health by identifying nutritional deficiencies and suggesting the application of the correct nutrient balance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stories From the Field: A Female Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:16:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the global agricultural landscape evolves, the role of women in farming is increasingly recognised as a vital force for sustainable development. In our “Stories from the Field” series, we seek to highlight the experiences of our farmers and agronomists across Africa. This article focuses on some of the women in Uganda who leverage &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; to enhance their agricultural practices, boost their maize yields, and improve their quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Update: Our New Image-Based Pest and Disease Feature</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:26:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we are proud of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; service and its ability to improve farmers&amp;rsquo; crop yield and soil health. Our service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers on WhatsApp, giving them personalized nutrient plans and essential agronomic advice for their crops and soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Agronomist offers farmers &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/"&gt;many helpful agronomic services&lt;/a&gt;, including a diagnostic pest and disease feature that asks farmers questions about their plants&amp;rsquo; growth and any issues they notice that concern them, for example, insect larvae, lesions, leaf discoloration, or head smut. The information is then processed by our scientific model, which provides a likely diagnosis and suggests treatments. It can also estimate the potential impact on crop yields if the issue is not managed properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist: Feature Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:25:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Our new generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other essential agronomic advice for their plots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/"&gt;we have launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for maize and rice&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, preparations are underway to launch Virtual Agronomist in Zambia for maize crops within the next few months. Virtual Agronomist supports the farmer with tailored advice throughout the season and can prompt and remind them of vital agronomic operations, for example, field mapping, soil data for their field, tailored nutrient plans, checking crop emergence, scouting for weeds, pests, and diseases, and harvesting. Through the features of our Virtual Agronomist service, farmers have the tools and advice they need to improve their crop health, yields and profits through better agronomic management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Nairobi Declaration 2024: Results from the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:30:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the 7th to the 9th of May 2024, the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit took place in Nairobi, Kenya. The summit brought together relevant key players in the agricultural industry to establish new policies and investments that will improve soil health and increase yield responses for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Kisitu, our director of operations at iSDA, was engaging and collaborating with government officials and industry stakeholders at AFSHS 2024, to encourage transformative change in the African agricultural sector. He brought awareness to &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, our open access soil health data map, and encouraged a continent-wide collaboration on soil data collection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA Soil: The Backbone of Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:29:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we have created the first field-level soil map for Africa, which estimates over twenty soil properties across the entire continent. These properties range from chemical factors, like aluminium and pH levels, to physical factors, such as clay content and slope angles, and soil nutrients like potassium and zinc. Our soil map at &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; stands out as the sole resource that predicts soil properties at 30 m resolution for the entire continent. This sets it apart from global soil maps, which typically offer resolutions of 250 m. Our higher spatial resolution enhances the precision of our predictions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Promising Future Yield Responses With Virtual Agronomist in Zambia</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:01:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Maize is a staple food for over half of the Zambian population and is cultivated by around eighty percent of smallholder farmers in the country. However, despite this, maize yield per hectare has often been significantly low, with farmers only averaging around 1.5 tonnes per hectare. Contributing factors to this low yield include drought brought about by climate change, pests and diseases, nutrient-deficient soils, and suboptimal agronomic practices. During our pilot programmes in the 2023/2024 season, iSDA partnered with IAPRI (Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute) to deliver tailored fertiliser recommendations to farmers in Zambia with an objective to increase maize yield by half and raise awareness of soil fertility levels across smallholder farms in the districts of Monze and Kapiri Mposhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International. Using Virtual Agronomist, our tailored advisory service, the Field Technicians generated specific nutrient recommendations for each farmer along with suggestions to improve agronomic practices. We demonstrated that the prospective yield and profit results with Virtual Agronomist were on average three times the farmer’s previous practice, when accompanied by good agronomic management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil used in malaria mapping study</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;iSDA’s soil and agronomy map iSDAsoil was recently used by scientists to create a framework to map the malaria exposure levels of Africans living in towns and cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though iSDAsoil is primarily used by iSDA as input for Virtual Agronomist, which determines the best use and combinations of fertilisers on their land, it also contains information on different chemical and physical soil properties that were used by these scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soil pH has an effect on the habitats of the Anopheles mosquito which transmits malaria. The scientists in this study therefore incorporated soil pH data to further determine the possible habitats of the mosquitoes. For this, they used open data from iSDAsoil at a depth of 0–20 cm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sustain Africa - increasing access to affordable fertiliser at scale</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As fertiliser prices continued to spike due to the Russia/Ukraine conflict, iSDA joined the &lt;a href="https://sustainafrica-initiative.org"&gt;Sustain Africa&lt;/a&gt; initiative in 2022 to increase African farmers&amp;rsquo; access to affordable fertiliser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great challenge when it comes to fertiliser use in Africa is the lack of precision in delivering the correct chemical formulation needed for each patch of farmland. Not all soils are formed or managed equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iSDA&amp;rsquo;s role in the Sustain Africa initiative has therefore been to deploy our app &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; to tackle this issue. The system was created to provide individual farmers in Africa, who usually do not have access to lab testing, the ability to assess the soil properties of their farmland and provide nutrient management plans for sustainable increases in crop yield.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CEO Announcement</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-08-ceo-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-08-ceo-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the iSDA Board and team, I am delighted to announce Jamie Collinson as our new Chief Executive Officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jamie has been instrumental to iSDA’s development since joining as Chief Technology Officer in 2020. His appointment to CEO reflects our firm belief, demonstrated over iSDA&amp;rsquo;s initial discovery phase, that a technology and science-driven approach will unlock agricultural productivity across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jamie is a world-class technologist, and has a demonstrated track record of growing early stage businesses to success. I have every confidence that his skills and leadership will take iSDA through our next phase of maturity into industry leadership, and accelerate our mission to bring individually tailored advice to millions of farmers across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA releases a large soil analysis dataset for Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-03-16-soil-data-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-03-16-soil-data-release/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;ISDA is proud to release a large dataset of analysed soil samples covering the African continent. These data are analysis-ready and do not require any preprocessing before usage. The dataset was collected and analysed according to protocols created by the African Soil Information Service (AfSIS) project (&lt;a href="https://worldagroforestry.org/sites/default/files/afsisSoilHealthTechSpecs_v1_smaller.pdf"&gt;Vågen T-G et al., 2010&lt;/a&gt;). AfSIS was an initiative funded by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, aimed at improving soil information across Africa. Data were collected and analysed between 2008 and 2020. In total, over 50,000 soil samples were collected across more than 15 countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Open access soil data for Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/open-soil-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/open-soil-data/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of our commitment to open access data, we are maintaining a soil analysis dataset for Africa. Our intention is to bring together as much soil data as possible in an analysis-ready format. We use this dataset to train the models that create the &lt;a href="https://isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; maps. We plan to regularly update this resource with additional soil data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="contributing-data"&gt;Contributing data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are maintaining a GitHub repository at &lt;a href="https://github.com/iSDA-Africa/open-soil-data"&gt;https://github.com/iSDA-Africa/open-soil-data&lt;/a&gt;. We welcome any pull requests contributing additional data. Alternatively you can &lt;a href="mailto:info@isda-africa.com"&gt;get in touch via email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Launch of Global Crop Nutrient Databases</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:17:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On 6th September 2022 a landmark new &lt;a href="https://cropnutrientdata.net"&gt;open data crop nutrition platform&lt;/a&gt; will launch. A partnership of the &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net"&gt;Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;, global research institutes and agtech companies like iSDA, the first outputs will be two databases focused on crop nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The databases will serve as a valuable open resource for agriculturual researchers and those in industry conducting field trials on soil fertility and crop nutrition. Users can both contribute to and benefit from the shared datasets, allowing critical data to be shared amongst researchers and commercial companies. The databases have already produced rapid results, including a &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fcr.2022.108578"&gt;published paper&lt;/a&gt; that estimates nutrient use and storage in maize.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grow-nourish-reward---bold-actions-for-resilient-food-systems"&gt;Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://agrf.org/AGRFSummit/"&gt;AGRF&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_79d32a3db560fdb0.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_8689c25d3c9fe67b.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_79d32a3db560fdb0.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directly supporting the aims of the summit is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>World Congress of Soil Science 2022</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-08-19-world-congress-of-soil-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:26:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-08-19-world-congress-of-soil-science/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Keith Shepherd (iSDA Chief Science Officer) presented a paper at the World Congress of Soil Science on &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667006222000284"&gt;A Global Soil Spectral Calibration &amp;amp; Estimation Service&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow in August 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper described ia freely available service that will allow users anywhere in the world to upload soil infrared spectra measurements and obtain estimates of multiple soil properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation can be viewed &lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/rec/share/hNgZ3n0lLAB-7gZ_5wRlQi0hYW73Ff3UZBklwp_1xR7rrwE_POx6evcdxcv8vi_s.KRw6Npwz43zN9aqR"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>As Featured In</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/asfeatured/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/asfeatured/</guid><description/></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Terms of Use</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/terms/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-who-we-are-and-how-to-contact-us"&gt;1. Who we are and how to contact us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soil maps and data presented within iSDAsoil (together “iSDAsoil”) are made available by Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (“Us”). We are registered in England and Wales under company number 11429051 and have our registered office at Rothamsted Research, West Common, Harpenden, Hertfordshire, AL5 2JQ. We are a social enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-by-accessing-and-using-isdasoil-you-accept-these-terms"&gt;2. By accessing and using iSDAsoil you accept these terms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By accessing and using iSDAsoil, you confirm that you accept and agree to comply with: these terms, the general &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/terms-of-use/"&gt;Terms of Use&lt;/a&gt;  governing our website and our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/privacy-policy/"&gt;Privacy and Cookie Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Privacy &amp; Cookie Policy</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/privacy-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (iSDA) (we, us, our) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This privacy policy aims to give you information on how iSDA processes your personal data when we collect personal data from you or that you provide to us through your use of the iSDA website, in particular how we go about keeping it secure at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Terms and Conditions for Using Virtual Agronomist Co-Pilot</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/copilot-terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/copilot-terms/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-acceptance-of-terms"&gt;1. Acceptance of Terms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using the Virtual Agronomist Co-pilot, you agree to these terms and conditions. If you do not agree, please do not use the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-service-description"&gt;2. Service Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the iSDAsoil map, the Virtual Agronomist Co-pilot delivers precise agricultural advice to optimize farming decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3-charges-and-payments"&gt;3. Charges and Payments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be a charge for using the Virtual Agronomist Co-pilot. Charges will be disclosed at the time of service initiation. All payments are due upon receipt and are non-refundable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Terms of Use</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/terms-of-use/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/terms-of-use/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Your use of our website is subject to the following terms and, by using our website, you agree to be legally bound by them. Please read these terms carefully before using our website. We may revise these terms from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-terms-and-conditions-for-the-use-of-this-website"&gt;1. Terms and Conditions for the use of this website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ‘Terms of Use’ policy sets out the terms between you and us under which you may access the iSDA websites. For the purposes of this terms of use policy “we”, “us”, “our” and “iSDA” means:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/contact-us/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/contact-us/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Team</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/team/</guid><description/></item><item><title>iSDA introduces the Virtual Agronomist App to the International Fertiliser Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February 2021 the iSDA team demonstrated the &lt;strong&gt;prototype app “Virtual Agronomist”&lt;/strong&gt; to the International Fertilizer Association (IFA). &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8GyxpSyeWs"&gt;The recorded webinar is available to view on YouTube.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting and answering the many user questions were members of the iSDA team: Jonathan Crouch, CEO; Jamie Collinson, CTO; Monica Cross, Head of Operations; Matt Miller, Lead Data Scientist; and Keith Shepherd, Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science. The webinar was chaired by Achim Dobermann, Chief Scientist at IFA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AfCPA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="notes-from-the-first-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture-8th-to-10th-december-2020"&gt;Notes from the first African Conference on Precision Agriculture, 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December 2020.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session was hosted by Jonathan Crouch (CEO, iSDA) with contributions from Matt Miller (Lead Data Scientist, iSDA), Jamie Collinson (CTO, iSDA), and Keith Shepherd (Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science, iSDA). The Panel comprised Praveen Singh (Agronomist, Indorama), Pieter Pypers (Senior Agronomist, International Institute of Tropical Agriculture), and Rik van den Bosch (Director, International Soil Reference and Information Centre).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>University of Aberdeen’s research project to tackle land loss in Ethiopia, utilises iSDAsoil</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;David McBey and Michael Martin from the University of Aberdeen speak to iSDA about how they are using the iSDAsoil resource to underpin the tools developed for their project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project – &lt;a href="https://www.abdn.ac.uk/news/14502/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reducing land degradation and carbon loss from Ethiopia’s soils to strengthen livelihoods and resilience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – is funded through a £1,000,000 grant from the &lt;a href="https://www.ukri.org/our-work/collaborating-internationally/global-challenges-research-fund/"&gt;UKRI Global Challenges Research Fund (GCRF)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_9d1e76cc6d8a0ca2.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_acc0548fdbebbfe4.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_9d1e76cc6d8a0ca2.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="david-mcbey-describes-the-project-aims-and-background"&gt;David McBey describes the project aims and background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My background is that I’m a social scientist. I’m employed on this project as an environmental modeller. We’re most interested in Ethiopia, because there’s a lot of degraded land there. I think it is about a quarter of the land, which impacts about a third of the population.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ASA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from the Special symposium on Translating Visionary Science for Excellence in African Agronomy at The American Society of Agronomy (ASA), the Crop Science Society of America (CSSA), and the Soil Science Society of America (SSSA) International Annual Meeting. 10th to 11th November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/"&gt;View the recorded videos from the conference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="african-soils-at-30-m-resolution-a-breakthrough-for-low-cost-agronomic-advisory"&gt;African soils at 30-m resolution. A breakthrough for low-cost agronomic advisory.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by &lt;strong&gt;Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt;. Chief Scientist, International Fertiliser Association.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Launch</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; previously launched on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; October 2020 and is an open access soil property map with 30m resolution for Africa. iSDA has collaborated with &lt;a href="https://www.worldagroforestry.org/"&gt;ICRAF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.rothamsted.ac.uk/"&gt;Rothamsted Research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://envirometrix.nl/"&gt;Envirometrix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gilab.rs/"&gt;GiLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://multione.hr/home.html"&gt;MultiOne&lt;/a&gt; to gather the immense dataset which underpins this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using on-site soil samples and computer modelling, a detailed and interactive image is produced displaying multiple properties of the soil throughout Africa. The high resolution of the data (24 billion data points) means that a single farm can identify the soil type accurate to a particular field. iSDAsoil also takes into account the depth of soil and the type of underlying bedrock to predict the full picture of soil status across the country. Where there are data gaps, iSDAsoil will be improved upon with further data received from dedicated soil agronomists.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>International Fertilizer Association Webinar 26 February 2021</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-information-revolution-in-africa-introducing-isdasoil"&gt;An information revolution in Africa? Introducing iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="26-february-2021-3pm-to-4pm-cet"&gt;26 February 2021, 3pm to 4pm CET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFA, the International Fertilizer Association is holding a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_UwuVtU-VTziZIJ1MTUtQlg"&gt;free webinar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focusing on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;. IFA’s Members include fertilizer producers, traders and distributors, as well as their associations, service providers to the industry, research organizations, and non-governmental organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for a live demonstration of iSDAsoil with the team, and a discussion with &lt;strong&gt;IFA Chief Scientist Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt; on what this mapping can mean for the future of farming in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the AfCPA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, the iSDA team made two presentations at The 1st African Conference on Precision Agriculture (AfCPA) in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="an-introduction-to-isdasoil"&gt;An introduction to iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Crouch, CEO of iSDA presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the history of digital soil mapping in Africa, the improvements made in iSDAsoil, and some applications of the resource:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MgX3tmDtbps?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-isdasoil-interactive-workshop"&gt;The iSDAsoil interactive workshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iSDA team then held an in-depth interactive session on iSDAsoil. This consisted of a live demo of iSDAsoil’s functionality, an expert panel discussion, and Q&amp;amp;A. The panel discussion members were:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the ASA-CSSA-SSSA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, the iSDA team made two presentations at The American Society of Agronomy, the Crop Science Society of America, and the Soil Science Society of America (ASA-CSSA-SSSA) Conference. This international virtual conference ran from the 9-13 November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achim Dobermann of the iSDA Board presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the problem space, importance of the breakthrough, and its potential applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EWbosAsGvGE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Achim Dobermann presents iSDAsoil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Decision Science</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/decision-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/decision-science/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Our approach is heavily rooted in decision science, with the aim of improving the quality of decision making by farmers and support services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming anywhere is typified by high investment risks, due to uncertainties in weather, pests and diseases, labour availability, responses to inputs, market prices, and climate change, to name a few. Risks are particularly acute in sub-Saharan Africa smallholder systems due to large spatial and temporal variability in all these factors, coupled with large impacts due to low incomes, vulnerable households, and the high price of inputs. High decision risk also stifles adoption of improved practices. The scarcity of reliable data further impairs delivering sound agronomic advisory to reduce decision risk. And yet current agronomic advice fails to communicate risk to farmers, or to help them learn how to reduce risks or promote opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Diagnostics</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/diagnostics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;iSDA is committed to diagnosing yield and profit limiting constraints. We do this at an individual field level to help farmers prioritise their investments, and at a project level to help aggregators target support services to farmers. Our applications help field officers quantitatively assess a wide range of yield constraints, ranging from plant nutrient deficiencies to soil structural constraints, and offer solutions for overcoming them. The constraints are diagnosed through observable indicators, in some cases with follow-up laboratory analyses. iSDA’s Bayesian approach provides for updating of our models over time based on observed cases and outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Scientific publications</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/publications/</guid><description>&lt;div style="border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.cabidigitallibrary.org/doi/10.31220/agriRxiv.2025.00332"&gt;Virtual Agronomist - an AI-assisted chatbot for guiding crop management decisions of smallholder farmers in Africa.&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Shepherd KD, Miller MAE, Kisitu B, Miles BG, Gbedevi K, Chunga PZ, Wairimu Thuo AG, Musiiwa RF, Gyampo ED, Cross M, Dobermann A and Collinson J
 &lt;br&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;2025&lt;/b&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 
 &lt;/p&gt;

 
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 
 

 &lt;div style="border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;
 
 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/su14094883"&gt;Mid-Infrared Reflectance Spectroscopy for Estimation of Soil Properties of Alfisols from Eastern India. Sustainability 14: 4883.&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Hati, K.M. Sinha, N., ..., Shepherd, K, Patra, A.K., Chaudhari, S.K.
 &lt;br&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;2022&lt;/b&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Soil-plant spectral diagnostics</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spectral-diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spectral-diagnostics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;iSDA has considerable experience with use of sensors for rapid assessment of soil and plant health, as part of our wider work on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/science/diagnostics"&gt;diagnostics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iSDA&amp;rsquo;s Chief Scientist, Keith Shepherd, pioneered the use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy for soil and plant analysis in Africa from the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s and has developed several global soil spectral libraries (see references below). He has helped establish soil spectroscopy in over 20 African laboratories, as well as in India, UK and USA.He has led the development of the &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soisec.2022.100061"&gt;Global Soil Spectral Library and Estimation Service&lt;/a&gt;, which aims to provide a free resource for estimating soil properties from anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Spatial Agronomy</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spatial-agronomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spatial-agronomy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Open access geospatial datasets are what underpin iSDA&amp;rsquo;s approach to Spatial Agronomy. Satellites are constantly monitoring the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface, allowing us to understand what is currently happening in any field. Many satellite missions have been orbiting the Earth for a long time - since the 1970&amp;rsquo;s, in the case of the Landsat missions. This means we can see how a field has been managed in the past few decades. We are also able to peer into the future using weather forecasts. Bringing all of this information together can help agronomists monitor their fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Privacy Policy</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist-privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist-privacy-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iSDA built the Virtual Agronomist app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by iSDA and is intended for use as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is used to inform visitors regarding our policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use our Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use our Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that we collect is used for providing and improving the Service. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>