<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nigeria on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/nigeria/</link><description>Recent content in Nigeria on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 11:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/nigeria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA and KPLUSS Partner to Bring Cutting-Edge Agronomic Advisory to Farmers in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-wih-kpluss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 11:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-wih-kpluss/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we believe that knowledge is the most powerful tool a farmer can have. That is why we are excited to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.kpluss.com/en-us/">KPLUSS Fertilizers Kenya Ltd.&lt;/a>, a collaboration set to revolutionise how farmers access agronomic advice and optimise their fertiliser applications for better yields and higher profits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this partnership, we will introduce our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> to farmers within the KPLUSS network, providing them with expert guidance on the best agronomic practices in a way that is both scalable and financially sustainable. This year, we hope to reach 1,000 farmers growing rice, coffee, beans, sorghum, and potatoes across the Kirinyaga and Meru counties in Kenya.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Update: Our Growing Partnership with Niger Foods</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/niger-foods-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/niger-foods-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a step toward advancing agriculture in Nigeria, we have partnered with &lt;a href="https://nigerfoods.com">Niger Foods&lt;/a> to deliver AI-powered advisory services to farmers in the Niger State. Through this collaboration, we deploy our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a>, providing maize, soybean, and rice farmers with real-time, data-driven insights to optimise crop management, improve soil health, and increase yields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having launched earlier this year, the initiative aims to support 10,000 farmers initially, expanding to 50,000 by the end of 2025. By leveraging technology to enhance productivity, this partnership is set to transform farming practices, improve profitability, and promote sustainability, creating a more resilient future for agriculture in Nigeria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA Africa Announces Exciting Partnership With Niger Foods</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-working-in-partnership-with-niger-foods-to-revolutionise-agriculture-with-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 15:16:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-working-in-partnership-with-niger-foods-to-revolutionise-agriculture-with-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a significant step towards transforming agriculture in Nigeria, we are excited to announce a groundbreaking partnership with &lt;a href="https://nigerfoods.com">Niger Foods&lt;/a> to deliver AI-powered advisory services to farmers in the Niger State!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of this partnership, we will deploy our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> to provide maize, soybean, and rice farmers with real-time, data-driven insights and advice to enhance crop management and increase yields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our service will provide personalised recommendations for essential agricultural practices, including fertiliser application and pest control, tailored to the unique conditions of each farm and will assist the farmers in improving their soil health by identifying nutritional deficiencies and suggesting the application of the correct nutrient balance.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>