<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kenya on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/kenya/</link><description>Recent content in Kenya on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 11:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/kenya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA and KPLUSS Partner to Bring Cutting-Edge Agronomic Advisory to Farmers in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-kpluss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 11:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-kpluss/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we believe that knowledge is the most powerful tool a farmer can have. That is why we are excited to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.kpluss.com/en-us/">KPLUSS Fertilizers Kenya Ltd.&lt;/a>, a collaboration set to revolutionise how farmers access agronomic advice and optimise their fertiliser applications for better yields and higher profits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this partnership, we will introduce our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> to farmers within the KPLUSS network, providing them with expert guidance on the best agronomic practices in a way that is both scalable and financially sustainable. This year, we hope to reach 1,000 farmers growing rice, coffee, beans, sorghum, and potatoes across the Kirinyaga and Meru counties in Kenya.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist Featured by Voice of America: Transforming Farming in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we are committed to revolutionising agriculture across Africa by empowering farmers with valuable agronomic knowledge. Our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual_agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory service&lt;/a> is designed to equip farmers with actionable insights tailored to their unique needs. Recent testimonials from Mwea, Kenya, where rice farming thrives, reveal the profound impact of this technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohammed Yusuf from &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com">Voice of America&lt;/a> recently visited farmers in Mwea, including Henry Gichobi, who shared how Virtual Agronomist has transformed his approach to farming. By leveraging Virtual Agronomist’s AI-driven analysis, Henry now makes data-informed decisions about fertilisers and chemicals, resulting in a dramatic increase in yield. &amp;ldquo;Before this technology, I was harvesting less than 20 bags. Now, I harvest 26 bags and above,&amp;rdquo; he said. With precise satellite imagery and soil nutrient data, Henry receives recommendations that maximise his productivity while reducing unnecessary input costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Nairobi Declaration 2024: Results from the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:30:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>From the 7th to the 9th of May 2024, the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit took place in Nairobi, Kenya. The summit brought together relevant key players in the agricultural industry to establish new policies and investments that will improve soil health and increase yield responses for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce Kisitu, our director of operations at iSDA, was engaging and collaborating with government officials and industry stakeholders at AFSHS 2024, to encourage transformative change in the African agricultural sector. He brought awareness to &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil&lt;/a>, our open access soil health data map, and encouraged a continent-wide collaboration on soil data collection.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>