<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA's Chief Scientist Dr. Keith Shepherd Wins 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rabat, Morocco – November 19, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; – iSDA is proud to announce that Dr. Keith Shepherd, Chief Scientist, has been awarded the 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award. The award was presented yesterday during the IFA Strategic Forum in Rabat, Morocco, recognizing Dr. Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s contributions to plant nutrition research and sustainable agricultural development across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-testament-to-scientific-excellence-and-real-world-impact"&gt;A Testament to Scientific Excellence and Real-World Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shepherd was selected by the Scientific Panel on Responsible Plant Nutrition (SPRPN). The panel was particularly impressed by the clarity of achievements from his research, which spans from significant scientific innovation to large-scale, tangible impact on the ground, delivering solutions that directly benefit smallholder farmers across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA at COP30: Bringing Africa's Climate-Ready Farmers to the Global Stage</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="belém-brazil--november-12-14-2025"&gt;Belém, Brazil | November 12-14, 2025&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in our history, Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (iSDA) took our place at COP30, the world&amp;rsquo;s most important climate conference. As delegates from nearly 200 countries gathered in Belém, Brazil, at the very edge of the Amazon rainforest, we delivered a powerful message: building climate resilience for Africa&amp;rsquo;s smallholder farmers isn&amp;rsquo;t a future promise. It needs to happen now, at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A month of momentum for Virtual Agronomist and a look ahead to COP30</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/month-of-momentum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:01:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/month-of-momentum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Bruce Kisitu, Director of Operations, Africa.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past month has been one of the most energising periods I’ve experienced in my time with iSDA. In the space of just a few weeks we had the privilege of engaging with some of the most important conversations shaping the future of African agriculture, while also witnessing the ever-growing tangible impact of our work on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Africa Food Systems Forum in Dakar, the energy in meeting rooms, panel discussions and exhibition halls was palpable. The urgency around food security, resilience and inclusive growth could not have been clearer. iSDA was proud to contribute a science-driven, tech perspective, demonstrating that scalable digital solutions are not a distant possibility - they are happening today. Our AI-advisory tool, Virtual Agronomist, has already been adopted by over 250,000 smallholder farmers, and, in recent weeks we have been seeing an extraordinary surge of around 4,000 new registrations every single day! These numbers are not just statistics - they represent households making more informed decisions, fields being managed with greater precision and harvests that have a better chance of withstanding climate uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2024 in Review: Celebrating a Year of Milestones and Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2024 comes to an end, our team at iSDA are proud to look back on a year marked by progress, innovation, and meaningful impact. This year has been a significant step forward in our mission to transform smallholder farming across Africa through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;, empowering farmers with tailored, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From expanding our reach to enhancing the accuracy of our AI-driven advice, we have seen firsthand how Virtual Agronomist can support sustainable farming practices, improve yields, and unlock potential for communities that rely on agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist at the CPCN Seminar: Revolutionising Agronomic Advice for Farmers Across Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where smallholder farmers face increasing challenges in achieving sustainable productivity, technology has emerged as a powerful ally. At the recent CPCN seminar, our innovative &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; took center stage. This cutting-edge tool delivers personalised agronomic advice directly to farmers via WhatsApp, bridging the gap between scientific insights and on-the-ground farming practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net"&gt;Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition (CPCN)&lt;/a&gt; seminar is coordinated by Dr Canon Engoke, Senior Scientist at the &lt;a href="https://www.apni.net"&gt;African Plant Nutrition Institute&lt;/a&gt; based in Nairobi, Kenya. The CPCN serves as a dynamic platform where companies, research institutes, universities, NGOs, and national programs collaborate to share expertise and data. It fosters the co-creation of aligned crop nutrition principles, standards, algorithms, and other vital resources. The seminar provides a hub for innovation, aiming to accelerate the development of effective, evidence-based digital crop nutrition advisory solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Showcasing Virtual Agronomist at the 3rd African Conference on Precision Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/showcasing-virtual-agronomist-at-the-3rd-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:09:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/showcasing-virtual-agronomist-at-the-3rd-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We were thrilled to make a significant impact at the &lt;a href="https://paafrica.org"&gt;3rd African Conference of Precision Agriculture (AfCPA)&lt;/a&gt;, held in Marrakech, Morocco, from December 3rd to 5th, 2024. Representing iSDA, our Southern Africa agronomist, Paul Zauzau Chunga, delivered a presentation to showcase our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="highlighting-the-power-of-the-virtual-agronomist"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlighting the Power of the Virtual Agronomist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul’s presentation showcased the remarkable achievements of our Virtual Agronomist service, with a focus on its deployment for four key crops: sunflower and lowland rice in Tanzania, maize in Côte d’Ivoire and Uganda, and sorghum in Uganda. Backed by strong data, we demonstrated how the implementation of Virtual Agronomist significantly boosts agricultural productivity for small-holder farmers:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Nairobi Declaration 2024: Results from the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:30:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the 7th to the 9th of May 2024, the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit took place in Nairobi, Kenya. The summit brought together relevant key players in the agricultural industry to establish new policies and investments that will improve soil health and increase yield responses for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Kisitu, our director of operations at iSDA, was engaging and collaborating with government officials and industry stakeholders at AFSHS 2024, to encourage transformative change in the African agricultural sector. He brought awareness to &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, our open access soil health data map, and encouraged a continent-wide collaboration on soil data collection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Launch of Global Crop Nutrient Databases</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:17:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On 6th September 2022 a landmark new &lt;a href="https://cropnutrientdata.net"&gt;open data crop nutrition platform&lt;/a&gt; will launch. A partnership of the &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net"&gt;Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;, global research institutes and agtech companies like iSDA, the first outputs will be two databases focused on crop nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The databases will serve as a valuable open resource for agriculturual researchers and those in industry conducting field trials on soil fertility and crop nutrition. Users can both contribute to and benefit from the shared datasets, allowing critical data to be shared amongst researchers and commercial companies. The databases have already produced rapid results, including a &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fcr.2022.108578"&gt;published paper&lt;/a&gt; that estimates nutrient use and storage in maize.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grow-nourish-reward---bold-actions-for-resilient-food-systems"&gt;Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://agrf.org/AGRFSummit/"&gt;AGRF&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_79d32a3db560fdb0.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_8689c25d3c9fe67b.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_79d32a3db560fdb0.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directly supporting the aims of the summit is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>World Congress of Soil Science 2022</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-08-19-world-congress-of-soil-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:26:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-08-19-world-congress-of-soil-science/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Keith Shepherd (iSDA Chief Science Officer) presented a paper at the World Congress of Soil Science on &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667006222000284"&gt;A Global Soil Spectral Calibration &amp;amp; Estimation Service&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow in August 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper described ia freely available service that will allow users anywhere in the world to upload soil infrared spectra measurements and obtain estimates of multiple soil properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation can be viewed &lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/rec/share/hNgZ3n0lLAB-7gZ_5wRlQi0hYW73Ff3UZBklwp_1xR7rrwE_POx6evcdxcv8vi_s.KRw6Npwz43zN9aqR"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AfCPA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="notes-from-the-first-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture-8th-to-10th-december-2020"&gt;Notes from the first African Conference on Precision Agriculture, 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December 2020.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session was hosted by Jonathan Crouch (CEO, iSDA) with contributions from Matt Miller (Lead Data Scientist, iSDA), Jamie Collinson (CTO, iSDA), and Keith Shepherd (Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science, iSDA). The Panel comprised Praveen Singh (Agronomist, Indorama), Pieter Pypers (Senior Agronomist, International Institute of Tropical Agriculture), and Rik van den Bosch (Director, International Soil Reference and Information Centre).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ASA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from the Special symposium on Translating Visionary Science for Excellence in African Agronomy at The American Society of Agronomy (ASA), the Crop Science Society of America (CSSA), and the Soil Science Society of America (SSSA) International Annual Meeting. 10th to 11th November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/"&gt;View the recorded videos from the conference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="african-soils-at-30-m-resolution-a-breakthrough-for-low-cost-agronomic-advisory"&gt;African soils at 30-m resolution. A breakthrough for low-cost agronomic advisory.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by &lt;strong&gt;Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt;. Chief Scientist, International Fertiliser Association.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Launch</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; previously launched on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; October 2020 and is an open access soil property map with 30m resolution for Africa. iSDA has collaborated with &lt;a href="https://www.worldagroforestry.org/"&gt;ICRAF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.rothamsted.ac.uk/"&gt;Rothamsted Research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://envirometrix.nl/"&gt;Envirometrix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gilab.rs/"&gt;GiLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://multione.hr/home.html"&gt;MultiOne&lt;/a&gt; to gather the immense dataset which underpins this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using on-site soil samples and computer modelling, a detailed and interactive image is produced displaying multiple properties of the soil throughout Africa. The high resolution of the data (24 billion data points) means that a single farm can identify the soil type accurate to a particular field. iSDAsoil also takes into account the depth of soil and the type of underlying bedrock to predict the full picture of soil status across the country. Where there are data gaps, iSDAsoil will be improved upon with further data received from dedicated soil agronomists.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>International Fertilizer Association Webinar 26 February 2021</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-information-revolution-in-africa-introducing-isdasoil"&gt;An information revolution in Africa? Introducing iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="26-february-2021-3pm-to-4pm-cet"&gt;26 February 2021, 3pm to 4pm CET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFA, the International Fertilizer Association is holding a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_UwuVtU-VTziZIJ1MTUtQlg"&gt;free webinar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focusing on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;. IFA’s Members include fertilizer producers, traders and distributors, as well as their associations, service providers to the industry, research organizations, and non-governmental organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for a live demonstration of iSDAsoil with the team, and a discussion with &lt;strong&gt;IFA Chief Scientist Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt; on what this mapping can mean for the future of farming in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the AfCPA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, the iSDA team made two presentations at The 1st African Conference on Precision Agriculture (AfCPA) in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="an-introduction-to-isdasoil"&gt;An introduction to iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Crouch, CEO of iSDA presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the history of digital soil mapping in Africa, the improvements made in iSDAsoil, and some applications of the resource:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MgX3tmDtbps?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-isdasoil-interactive-workshop"&gt;The iSDAsoil interactive workshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iSDA team then held an in-depth interactive session on iSDAsoil. This consisted of a live demo of iSDAsoil’s functionality, an expert panel discussion, and Q&amp;amp;A. The panel discussion members were:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the ASA-CSSA-SSSA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, the iSDA team made two presentations at The American Society of Agronomy, the Crop Science Society of America, and the Soil Science Society of America (ASA-CSSA-SSSA) Conference. This international virtual conference ran from the 9-13 November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achim Dobermann of the iSDA Board presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the problem space, importance of the breakthrough, and its potential applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EWbosAsGvGE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Achim Dobermann presents iSDAsoil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>