<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uganda on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/uganda/</link><description>Recent content in Uganda on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:52:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/uganda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A New Chapter for Agriculture in Uganda: Our Partnership With Sasakawa Africa Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-sasakawa-africa-association/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:52:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/our-partnership-with-sasakawa-africa-association/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are excited to announce our groundbreaking partnership with &lt;a href="https://saa-safe.org">Sasakawa Africa Association (SAA)&lt;/a> in Uganda, a company who have been working alongside smallholder farmers since 1986. SAA partners closely with national agricultural extension services in Ethiopia, Mali, Nigeria, and Uganda to assist smallholder farmers throughout the agricultural value chain. Its mission is to enhance farmers’ incomes and improve food and nutrition security by promoting sustainable, regenerative, and nutrition-sensitive agricultural innovations while building the capacity of extension agents and farmers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empowering Farmers in Uganda: Our New Partnership with Ecolife</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-announces-partnership-with-ecolife/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:26:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-announces-partnership-with-ecolife/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we believe that data-driven solutions can transform agriculture, especially when combined with local expertise and on-the-ground support. We are thrilled to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.ecolifefoods.org/">Ecolife&lt;/a> in Kitula-Namayumba, Uganda, aimed at launching our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> for 1,000 maize farmers. This initiative, which began in September 2024, is focused on driving improved yield, quality, and profitability for local farmers while supporting Ecolife’s mission of sustainable agricultural growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stories From the Field: A Female Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:16:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the global agricultural landscape evolves, the role of women in farming is increasingly recognised as a vital force for sustainable development. In our “Stories from the Field” series, we seek to highlight the experiences of our farmers and agronomists across Africa. This article focuses on some of the women in Uganda who leverage &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> to enhance their agricultural practices, boost their maize yields, and improve their quality of life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>