<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Farmers on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/farmers/</link><description>Recent content in Farmers on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/farmers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Precision Agriculture Delivers: Coffee Farmers in Kenya Achieve 50% Yield Increase with Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/precision-agriculture-delivers-coffee-farmers-in-kenya-achieve-50-yield-increase-with-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/precision-agriculture-delivers-coffee-farmers-in-kenya-achieve-50-yield-increase-with-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee is an important cash crop to Kenya’s economy, contributing up to 10% of Kenya’s total agricultural export revenue and supporting the livelihood of more than 700,000 farmers. Poor agronomic practices, pests, diseases, low-yielding varieties and unstable market prices have contributed to low production. ISDA&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Agronomist (VA) leverages Artificial Intelligence (AI) to support smallholder farmers with farm-specific agronomic advice. Virtual Agronomist is a scientific AI tool that is delivered through a WhatsApp chatbot and advises farmers on fertiliser, pests, diseases, weather and soils. It is offered for more than 20 crops, including coffee. &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One Youth Farmer, 15,000 Others Inspired</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/amos-spotlight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:48:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/amos-spotlight/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, digital agriculture is reshaping how young people see farming. Drones, climate apps, mobile advisory platforms are making agriculture look cool, profitable and modern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s working: the majority of digital agriculture users in Africa are aged 15–35, showing how technology is pulling a new generation back to farming. From Hello Tractor in Nigeria to DigiFarm in Kenya, young people are driving adoption. Projects like Hinga Weze in Rwanda and startups like M-Omulimisa in Uganda are proving the same thing: give youth the right tools, and they transform agriculture into a business worth staying in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Reaches 250,000 Farmers: Scaling Real Solutions, Fast</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/250000-unique-farmers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:38:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/250000-unique-farmers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just one month ago, we announced that Virtual Agronomist had reached more than 250,000 farm plots with locally tailored, AI-powered advice. Today, that figure already looks out of date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve now passed 350,000 farm plots, and for the first time, we can say we are directly serving a quarter of a million farmers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more than a milestone. It’s evidence of huge, rapid growth — and of the power of a model that is working at scale, and in reality, for African farmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beyond the Harvest: How Virtual Agronomist Is Doing More Than Improving Yields</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/doing-more-than-improving-yields/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:04:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/doing-more-than-improving-yields/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Last year’s income was quite high, so I decided to build a good house for me to live in, and this is what I am working on finalising.”&lt;/em&gt;
— Dorcas Macharia, smallholder farmer, Reru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, smallholder farmers face mounting challenges - unpredictable weather, rising input costs and limited access to expert guidance.
But change is underway, driven by a new generation of science-backed tools like iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-virtual-agronomist-works"&gt;How Virtual Agronomist Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Agronomist delivers personalised, expert advice via WhatsApp, tailored to each farmer’s soil,
crop and weather conditions. It guides decisions on fertiliser use, pest control and planting schedules - combining local data with cutting-edge science.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Advice in Action: Virtual Agronomist Delivers Higher Yields for Ugandan Sunflower Farmers</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/uganda-sunflower-farmers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:33:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/uganda-sunflower-farmers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Uganda’s agricultural sector plays a vital role in driving economic growth, reducing poverty and ensuring national food security.
Contributing around 24% to GDP and employing over 70% of the population, agriculture is the country’s economic backbone.
Yet with most farming rain-fed and subsistence-based, the sector remains highly vulnerable to climate change - especially to increasingly frequent and severe droughts.
By 2050, climate impacts are projected to cause economic losses of up to US$1.5 billion for smallholder farmers across Africa. Their livelihoods - and national food systems - are under growing threat.
That’s why iSDA is building tools that combine world-class science with cutting-edge technology to help farmers adapt.
At the centre of this work is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist (VA)&lt;/a&gt; - our AI-powered advisory tool, delivered via WhatsApp, that provides data-driven,
hyper-local advice to farmers across Africa. What makes VA different is its foundation in science: it generates fertiliser and nutrient management plans tailored to individual plots,
using high-resolution soil data from &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s most detailed soil mapping platform. By pairing soil diagnostics with real-time insights on pests, disease and weather,
Virtual Agronomist helps farmers make smarter decisions - boosting productivity and building resilience to climate shocks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why the Next Generation of Farm Advisory Needs More Than Just Cool Tech</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-the-next-generation-of-farm-advisory-needs-more-than-just-cool-tech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:58:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-the-next-generation-of-farm-advisory-needs-more-than-just-cool-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, millions of farmers face a fundamental challenge: they lack access to timely, tailored advice that can help them make confident decisions about their crops and soils.
This isn’t a new problem. What’s new is the tools at our disposal to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we believe the future of farm advisory is more than just tech. It’s about trust, science, systems - and scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-more-tech-doesnt-automatically-mean-better-advice"&gt;1. More Tech Doesn’t Automatically Mean Better Advice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, we’ve seen a surge in AI-powered platforms promising to revolutionise smallholder agriculture. And yes - technology is unlocking new possibilities. But when tech is deployed without a deep understanding of agronomy, local context or farmer realities, it risks repeating old mistakes in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>200,000 Plots and Counting: Celebrating One Year of Our Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory Service</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In its first year, our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has provided tailored nutrient recommendations for over 200,000 farm plots across Africa. This confirms our mission to empower African farmers with easy-to-access tailored, data-driven insights to enhance productivity, profitability, sustainability, and decision-making. Using our extensive knowledge base, &lt;a href="isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; soil analysis, and advisory engine, our service is designed to provide instant, personalised guidance throughout the farming season — helping farmers optimise crop health, manage resources efficiently, and navigate climate challenges with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Delivers 100,000 Tailored Advisories to African Smallholder Farmers in the First Year</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to share that iSDA’s &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has helped African farmers on over 100,000 plots - a fantastic milestone achieved in just one year since the launch of the AI expert advisory in February 2024! This achievement is more than a number - it is real impact. Thousands of farmers are now equipped with AI-powered, data-driven insights which helps them to instantaneously know their soil status (NPK values) and get a nutrient plan to adopt sustainable farming practices, improve their yields and increase their income.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unveiling the Impact of iSDA's Rice Harvest Data Survey in Mwea, Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/unveiling-the-impact-of-isda-rice-harvest-data-survey-in-mwea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:16:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/unveiling-the-impact-of-isda-rice-harvest-data-survey-in-mwea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rice production is central to Mwea’s agricultural identity, contributing significantly to Kenya’s food security and economy while supporting thousands of smallholder farmers. However, challenges such as resource inefficiencies, soil degradation, and the need for precise farming practices make it difficult to meet growing demands sustainably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tackle these issues, our team at iSDA conducted a retrospective cohort study to assess the impact of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; compared with normal Farmer Practice in the Mwea Rice Scheme in Kenya. Designed to deliver tailored, data-driven recommendations, our Virtual Agronomist advisory service aims to enhance farming practices and boost productivity for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2024 in Review: Celebrating a Year of Milestones and Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2024 comes to an end, our team at iSDA are proud to look back on a year marked by progress, innovation, and meaningful impact. This year has been a significant step forward in our mission to transform smallholder farming across Africa through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;, empowering farmers with tailored, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From expanding our reach to enhancing the accuracy of our AI-driven advice, we have seen firsthand how Virtual Agronomist can support sustainable farming practices, improve yields, and unlock potential for communities that rely on agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stories From the Field: A Female Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:16:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the global agricultural landscape evolves, the role of women in farming is increasingly recognised as a vital force for sustainable development. In our “Stories from the Field” series, we seek to highlight the experiences of our farmers and agronomists across Africa. This article focuses on some of the women in Uganda who leverage &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; to enhance their agricultural practices, boost their maize yields, and improve their quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Promising Future Yield Responses With Virtual Agronomist in Zambia</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:01:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Maize is a staple food for over half of the Zambian population and is cultivated by around eighty percent of smallholder farmers in the country. However, despite this, maize yield per hectare has often been significantly low, with farmers only averaging around 1.5 tonnes per hectare. Contributing factors to this low yield include drought brought about by climate change, pests and diseases, nutrient-deficient soils, and suboptimal agronomic practices. During our pilot programmes in the 2023/2024 season, iSDA partnered with IAPRI (Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute) to deliver tailored fertiliser recommendations to farmers in Zambia with an objective to increase maize yield by half and raise awareness of soil fertility levels across smallholder farms in the districts of Monze and Kapiri Mposhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International. Using Virtual Agronomist, our tailored advisory service, the Field Technicians generated specific nutrient recommendations for each farmer along with suggestions to improve agronomic practices. We demonstrated that the prospective yield and profit results with Virtual Agronomist were on average three times the farmer’s previous practice, when accompanied by good agronomic management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>