<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Featured on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/featured/</link><description>Recent content in Featured on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:26:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Update: Our New Image-Based Pest and Disease Feature</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:26:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</guid><description>At iSDA, we are proud of our Virtual Agronomist service and its ability to improve farmers&amp;rsquo; crop yield and soil health. Our service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers on WhatsApp, giving them personalized nutrient plans and essential agronomic advice for their crops and soil.
Virtual Agronomist offers farmers many helpful agronomic services, including a diagnostic pest and disease feature that asks farmers questions about their plants&amp;rsquo; growth and any issues they notice that concern them, for example, insect larvae, lesions, leaf discoloration, or head smut.</description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>We are thrilled to announce that our next generation Virtual Agronomist, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.
Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots.</description></item><item><title>iSDA Soil: The Backbone of Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:29:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>At iSDA, we have created the first field-level soil map for Africa, which estimates over twenty soil properties across the entire continent. These properties range from chemical factors, like aluminium and pH levels, to physical factors, such as clay content and slope angles, and soil nutrients like potassium and zinc. Our soil map at iSDAsoil stands out as the sole resource that predicts soil properties at 30 m resolution for the entire continent.</description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with Virtual Agronomist across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.
One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.
In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International.</description></item><item><title>iSDA releases a large soil analysis dataset for Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-03-16-soil-data-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-03-16-soil-data-release/</guid><description>ISDA is proud to release a large dataset of analysed soil samples covering the African continent. These data are analysis-ready and do not require any preprocessing before usage. The dataset was collected and analysed according to protocols created by the African Soil Information Service (AfSIS) project (Vågen T-G et al., 2010). AfSIS was an initiative funded by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, aimed at improving soil information across Africa. Data were collected and analysed between 2008 and 2020.</description></item><item><title>Launch of Global Crop Nutrient Databases</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:17:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</guid><description>On 6th September 2022 a landmark new open data crop nutrition platform will launch. A partnership of the Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition, global research institutes and agtech companies like iSDA, the first outputs will be two databases focused on crop nutrition.
The databases will serve as a valuable open resource for agriculturual researchers and those in industry conducting field trials on soil fertility and crop nutrition. Users can both contribute to and benefit from the shared datasets, allowing critical data to be shared amongst researchers and commercial companies.</description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems AGRF, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:
Virtual Agronomist Directly supporting the aims of the summit is Virtual Agronomist, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.</description></item></channel></rss>