<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual Agronomist on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/virtual-agronomist/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual Agronomist on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:01:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/virtual-agronomist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Promising Future Yield Responses With Virtual Agronomist in Zambia</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:01:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</guid><description>Maize is a staple food for over half of the Zambian population and is cultivated by around eighty percent of smallholder farmers in the country. However, despite this, maize yield per hectare has often been significantly low, with farmers only averaging around 1.5 tonnes per hectare. Contributing factors to this low yield include drought brought about by climate change, pests and diseases, nutrient-deficient soils, and suboptimal agronomic practices. During our pilot programmes in the 2023/2024 season, iSDA partnered with IAPRI (Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute) to deliver tailored fertiliser recommendations to farmers in Zambia with an objective to increase maize yield by half and raise awareness of soil fertility levels across smallholder farms in the districts of Monze and Kapiri Mposhi.</description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with Virtual Agronomist across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.
One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.
In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International.</description></item><item><title>iSDA introduces the Virtual Agronomist App to the International Fertilizer Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</guid><description>On 26th February 2021 the iSDA team demonstrated the prototype app “Virtual Agronomist” to the International Fertilizer Association (IFA). The recorded webinar is available to view on YouTube.
Presenting and answering the many user questions were members of the iSDA team: Jonathan Crouch, CEO; Jamie Collinson, CTO; Monica Cross, Head of Operations; Matt Miller, Lead Data Scientist; and Keith Shepherd, Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science. The webinar was chaired by Achim Dobermann, Chief Scientist at IFA.</description></item></channel></rss>