<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scientific Research and Innovation on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/</link><description>Recent content in Scientific Research and Innovation on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Decision Science</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/decision-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/decision-science/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our approach is heavily rooted in decision science, with the aim of improving the quality of decision making by farmers and support services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Farming anywhere is typified by high investment risks, due to uncertainties in weather, pests and diseases, labour availability, responses to inputs, market prices, and climate change, to name a few. Risks are particularly acute in sub-Saharan Africa smallholder systems due to large spatial and temporal variability in all these factors, coupled with large impacts due to low incomes, vulnerable households, and the high price of inputs. High decision risk also stifles adoption of improved practices. The scarcity of reliable data further impairs delivering sound agronomic advisory to reduce decision risk. And yet current agronomic advice fails to communicate risk to farmers, or to help them learn how to reduce risks or promote opportunities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diagnostics</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/diagnostics/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA is committed to diagnosing yield and profit limiting constraints. We do this at an individual field level to help farmers prioritise their investments, and at a project level to help aggregators target support services to farmers. Our applications help field officers quantitatively assess a wide range of yield constraints, ranging from plant nutrient deficiencies to soil structural constraints, and offer solutions for overcoming them. The constraints are diagnosed through observable indicators, in some cases with follow-up laboratory analyses. iSDA’s Bayesian approach provides for updating of our models over time based on observed cases and outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scientific publications</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/publications/</guid><description>&lt;div style="border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
 &lt;p>
 &lt;strong>
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.cabidigitallibrary.org/doi/10.31220/agriRxiv.2025.00332">Virtual Agronomist - an AI-assisted chatbot for guiding crop management decisions of smallholder farmers in Africa.&lt;/a>
 
 &lt;/strong>&lt;br>
 Shepherd KD, Miller MAE, Kisitu B, Miles BG, Gbedevi K, Chunga PZ, Wairimu Thuo AG, Musiiwa RF, Gyampo ED, Cross M, Dobermann A and Collinson J
 &lt;br>
 &lt;b>2025&lt;/b>
 &lt;/p>

 &lt;p>
 
 &lt;/p>

 
 &lt;/div>
 
 
 
 
 

 &lt;div style="border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
 &lt;p>
 &lt;strong>
 
 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/su14094883">Mid-Infrared Reflectance Spectroscopy for Estimation of Soil Properties of Alfisols from Eastern India. Sustainability 14: 4883.&lt;/a>
 
 &lt;/strong>&lt;br>
 Hati, K.M. Sinha, N., ..., Shepherd, K, Patra, A.K., Chaudhari, S.K.
 &lt;br>
 &lt;b>2022&lt;/b>
 &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soil-plant spectral diagnostics</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spectral-diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spectral-diagnostics/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA has considerable experience with use of sensors for rapid assessment of soil and plant health, as part of our wider work on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/science/diagnostics">diagnostics&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>iSDA&amp;rsquo;s Chief Scientist, Keith Shepherd, pioneered the use of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy for soil and plant analysis in Africa from the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s and has developed several global soil spectral libraries (see references below). He has helped establish soil spectroscopy in over 20 African laboratories, as well as in India, UK and USA.He has led the development of the &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soisec.2022.100061">Global Soil Spectral Library and Estimation Service&lt;/a>, which aims to provide a free resource for estimating soil properties from anywhere in the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spatial Agronomy</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spatial-agronomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/science/spatial-agronomy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Open access geospatial datasets are what underpin iSDA&amp;rsquo;s approach to Spatial Agronomy. Satellites are constantly monitoring the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface, allowing us to understand what is currently happening in any field. Many satellite missions have been orbiting the Earth for a long time - since the 1970&amp;rsquo;s, in the case of the Landsat missions. This means we can see how a field has been managed in the past few decades. We are also able to peer into the future using weather forecasts. Bringing all of this information together can help agronomists monitor their fields.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>