<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Climate on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/climate/</link><description>Recent content in Climate on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA's Chief Scientist Dr. Keith Shepherd Wins 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rabat, Morocco – November 19, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; – iSDA is proud to announce that Dr. Keith Shepherd, Chief Scientist, has been awarded the 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award. The award was presented yesterday during the IFA Strategic Forum in Rabat, Morocco, recognizing Dr. Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s contributions to plant nutrition research and sustainable agricultural development across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-testament-to-scientific-excellence-and-real-world-impact"&gt;A Testament to Scientific Excellence and Real-World Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shepherd was selected by the Scientific Panel on Responsible Plant Nutrition (SPRPN). The panel was particularly impressed by the clarity of achievements from his research, which spans from significant scientific innovation to large-scale, tangible impact on the ground, delivering solutions that directly benefit smallholder farmers across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA at COP30: Bringing Africa's Climate-Ready Farmers to the Global Stage</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="belém-brazil--november-12-14-2025"&gt;Belém, Brazil | November 12-14, 2025&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in our history, Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (iSDA) took our place at COP30, the world&amp;rsquo;s most important climate conference. As delegates from nearly 200 countries gathered in Belém, Brazil, at the very edge of the Amazon rainforest, we delivered a powerful message: building climate resilience for Africa&amp;rsquo;s smallholder farmers isn&amp;rsquo;t a future promise. It needs to happen now, at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>