<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Climate on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/climate/</link><description>Recent content in Climate on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Virtual Agronomist Detected Downy Mildew in Malawi Before the Official Outbreak</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/how-virtual-agronomist-detected-downy-mildew-in-malawi-before-the-official-outbreak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/how-virtual-agronomist-detected-downy-mildew-in-malawi-before-the-official-outbreak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-moving world of agriculture, timing is everything. A few days can mean the difference between a healthy harvest and devastating crop loss. This is the story of how one farmer used Virtual Agronomist to detect a disease outbreak before government authorities even announced it. This is the proof that AI-powered agronomy isn&amp;rsquo;t just convenient; it&amp;rsquo;s transformative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During one of his usual morning inspections on his small maize field in Lilongwe, Malawi, Paul Chunga noticed something troubling on his leaves. He pulled out his phone, opened WhatsApp, and messaged Virtual Agronomist. Within minutes, he had his answer: &lt;strong&gt;Downy Mildew.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Supporting Healthy Soils for Healthy Cities: Virtual Agronomist's Role in Urban and Peri-Urban Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 marks the United Nations World Soil Day (WSD). This year&amp;rsquo;s theme, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Healthy soils for healthy cities,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; highlights the critical role of soils in urban areas. Healthy urban soils filter water, store carbon, regulate temperatures, support biodiversity and even sustain food production. With two-thirds of the world&amp;rsquo;s population expected to live in cities by 2050, there is an urgent need for a one health approach across urban spaces to sustain and restore the health of our soils, the health of our cities, ecosystems and people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA's Chief Scientist Dr. Keith Shepherd Wins 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rabat, Morocco – November 19, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; – iSDA is proud to announce that Dr. Keith Shepherd, Chief Scientist, has been awarded the 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award. The award was presented yesterday during the IFA Strategic Forum in Rabat, Morocco, recognizing Dr. Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s contributions to plant nutrition research and sustainable agricultural development across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-testament-to-scientific-excellence-and-real-world-impact"&gt;A Testament to Scientific Excellence and Real-World Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shepherd was selected by the Scientific Panel on Responsible Plant Nutrition (SPRPN). The panel was particularly impressed by the clarity of achievements from his research, which spans from significant scientific innovation to large-scale, tangible impact on the ground, delivering solutions that directly benefit smallholder farmers across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA at COP30: Bringing Africa's Climate-Ready Farmers to the Global Stage</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="belém-brazil--november-12-14-2025"&gt;Belém, Brazil | November 12-14, 2025&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in our history, Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (iSDA) took our place at COP30, the world&amp;rsquo;s most important climate conference. As delegates from nearly 200 countries gathered in Belém, Brazil, at the very edge of the Amazon rainforest, we delivered a powerful message: building climate resilience for Africa&amp;rsquo;s smallholder farmers isn&amp;rsquo;t a future promise. It needs to happen now, at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>