<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:16:04 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stories From the Field: A Female Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:16:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the global agricultural landscape evolves, the role of women in farming is increasingly recognised as a vital force for sustainable development. In our “Stories from the Field” series, we seek to highlight the experiences of our farmers and agronomists across Africa. This article focuses on some of the women in Uganda who leverage &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> to enhance their agricultural practices, boost their maize yields, and improve their quality of life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Update: Our New Image-Based Pest and Disease Feature</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:26:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we are proud of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> service and its ability to improve farmers&amp;rsquo; crop yield and soil health. Our service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers on WhatsApp, giving them personalized nutrient plans and essential agronomic advice for their crops and soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtual Agronomist offers farmers &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/">many helpful agronomic services&lt;/a>, including a diagnostic pest and disease feature that asks farmers questions about their plants&amp;rsquo; growth and any issues they notice that concern them, for example, insect larvae, lesions, leaf discoloration, or head smut. The information is then processed by our scientific model, which provides a likely diagnosis and suggests treatments. It can also estimate the potential impact on crop yields if the issue is not managed properly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist: Feature Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:25:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our new generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other essential agronomic advice for their plots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far, &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/">we have launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for maize and rice&lt;/a>. Additionally, preparations are underway to launch Virtual Agronomist in Zambia for maize crops within the next few months. Virtual Agronomist supports the farmer with tailored advice throughout the season and can prompt and remind them of vital agronomic operations, for example, field mapping, soil data for their field, tailored nutrient plans, checking crop emergence, scouting for weeds, pests, and diseases, and harvesting. Through the features of our Virtual Agronomist service, farmers have the tools and advice they need to improve their crop health, yields and profits through better agronomic management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Nairobi Declaration 2024: Results from the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:30:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/nairobi-declaration-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>From the 7th to the 9th of May 2024, the Africa Fertilizer and Soil Health Summit took place in Nairobi, Kenya. The summit brought together relevant key players in the agricultural industry to establish new policies and investments that will improve soil health and increase yield responses for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce Kisitu, our director of operations at iSDA, was engaging and collaborating with government officials and industry stakeholders at AFSHS 2024, to encourage transformative change in the African agricultural sector. He brought awareness to &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil&lt;/a>, our open access soil health data map, and encouraged a continent-wide collaboration on soil data collection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA Soil: The Backbone of Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:29:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we have created the first field-level soil map for Africa, which estimates over twenty soil properties across the entire continent. These properties range from chemical factors, like aluminium and pH levels, to physical factors, such as clay content and slope angles, and soil nutrients like potassium and zinc. Our soil map at &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil&lt;/a> stands out as the sole resource that predicts soil properties at 30 m resolution for the entire continent. This sets it apart from global soil maps, which typically offer resolutions of 250 m. Our higher spatial resolution enhances the precision of our predictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Promising Future Yield Responses With Virtual Agronomist in Zambia</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 13:01:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/promising-future-yield-responses-with-virtual-agronomist-in-zambia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maize is a staple food for over half of the Zambian population and is cultivated by around eighty percent of smallholder farmers in the country. However, despite this, maize yield per hectare has often been significantly low, with farmers only averaging around 1.5 tonnes per hectare. Contributing factors to this low yield include drought brought about by climate change, pests and diseases, nutrient-deficient soils, and suboptimal agronomic practices. During our pilot programmes in the 2023/2024 season, iSDA partnered with IAPRI (Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute) to deliver tailored fertiliser recommendations to farmers in Zambia with an objective to increase maize yield by half and raise awareness of soil fertility levels across smallholder farms in the districts of Monze and Kapiri Mposhi.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International. Using Virtual Agronomist, our tailored advisory service, the Field Technicians generated specific nutrient recommendations for each farmer along with suggestions to improve agronomic practices. We demonstrated that the prospective yield and profit results with Virtual Agronomist were on average three times the farmer’s previous practice, when accompanied by good agronomic management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil used in malaria mapping study</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA’s soil and agronomy map iSDAsoil was recently used by scientists to create a framework to map the malaria exposure levels of Africans living in towns and cities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though iSDAsoil is primarily used by iSDA as input for Virtual Agronomist, which determines the best use and combinations of fertilisers on their land, it also contains information on different chemical and physical soil properties that were used by these scientists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soil pH has an effect on the habitats of the Anopheles mosquito which transmits malaria. The scientists in this study therefore incorporated soil pH data to further determine the possible habitats of the mosquitoes. For this, they used open data from iSDAsoil at a depth of 0–20 cm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sustain Africa - increasing access to affordable fertiliser at scale</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>As fertiliser prices continued to spike due to the Russia/Ukraine conflict, iSDA joined the &lt;a href="https://sustainafrica-initiative.org">Sustain Africa&lt;/a> initiative in 2022 to increase African farmers&amp;rsquo; access to affordable fertiliser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The initiative is a partnership between multiple organisations including the International Fertilizer Association, Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, African Fertilizer, Agribusiness Partnership (AFAP) and AGRA. It has already targeted 1.5 million farmers across the continent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A great challenge when it comes to fertiliser use in Africa is the lack of precision in delivering the correct chemical formulation needed for each patch of farmland. Not all soils are formed or managed equally.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CEO Announcement</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-08-ceo-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-08-ceo-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>On behalf of the iSDA Board and team, I am delighted to announce Jamie Collinson as our new Chief Executive Officer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamie has been instrumental to iSDA’s development since joining as Chief Technology Officer in 2020. His appointment to CEO reflects our firm belief, demonstrated over iSDA&amp;rsquo;s initial discovery phase, that a technology and science-driven approach will unlock agricultural productivity across the African continent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamie is a world-class technologist, and has a demonstrated track record of growing early stage businesses to success. I have every confidence that his skills and leadership will take iSDA through our next phase of maturity into industry leadership, and accelerate our mission to bring individually tailored advice to millions of farmers across Africa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA releases a large soil analysis dataset for Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-03-16-soil-data-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-03-16-soil-data-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>ISDA is proud to release a large dataset of analysed soil samples covering the African continent. These data are analysis-ready and do not require any preprocessing before usage. The dataset was collected and analysed according to protocols created by the African Soil Information Service (AfSIS) project (&lt;a href="https://worldagroforestry.org/sites/default/files/afsisSoilHealthTechSpecs_v1_smaller.pdf">Vågen T-G et al., 2010&lt;/a>). AfSIS was an initiative funded by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, aimed at improving soil information across Africa. Data were collected and analysed between 2008 and 2020. In total, over 50,000 soil samples were collected across more than 15 countries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Launch of Global Crop Nutrient Databases</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:17:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-05-global-crop-nutrient-databases-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 6th September 2022 a landmark new &lt;a href="https://cropnutrientdata.net">open data crop nutrition platform&lt;/a> will launch. A partnership of the &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net">Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition&lt;/a>, global research institutes and agtech companies like iSDA, the first outputs will be two databases focused on crop nutrition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The databases will serve as a valuable open resource for agriculturual researchers and those in industry conducting field trials on soil fertility and crop nutrition. Users can both contribute to and benefit from the shared datasets, allowing critical data to be shared amongst researchers and commercial companies. The databases have already produced rapid results, including a &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fcr.2022.108578">published paper&lt;/a> that estimates nutrient use and storage in maize.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grow-nourish-reward---bold-actions-for-resilient-food-systems">Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://agrf.org/AGRFSummit/">AGRF&lt;/a>, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
 
 

 
 

 &lt;img 
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu16232441485075464858.png" 
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu16683027965965773915.png 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu16232441485075464858.png 1x"
 class="img-fluid">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="virtual-agronomist">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Directly supporting the aims of the summit is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>World Congress of Soil Science 2022</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-08-19-world-congress-of-soil-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:26:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-08-19-world-congress-of-soil-science/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keith Shepherd (iSDA Chief Science Officer) presented a paper at the World Congress of Soil Science on &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667006222000284">A Global Soil Spectral Calibration &amp;amp; Estimation Service&lt;/a> in Glasgow in August 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The paper described ia freely available service that will allow users anywhere in the world to upload soil infrared spectra measurements and obtain estimates of multiple soil properties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The presentation can be viewed &lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/rec/share/hNgZ3n0lLAB-7gZ_5wRlQi0hYW73Ff3UZBklwp_1xR7rrwE_POx6evcdxcv8vi_s.KRw6Npwz43zN9aqR">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA introduces the Virtual Agronomist App to the International Fertilizer Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 26&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> February 2021 the iSDA team demonstrated the &lt;strong>prototype app “Virtual Agronomist”&lt;/strong> to the International Fertilizer Association (IFA). &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8GyxpSyeWs">The recorded webinar is available to view on YouTube.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presenting and answering the many user questions were members of the iSDA team: Jonathan Crouch, CEO; Jamie Collinson, CTO; Monica Cross, Head of Operations; Matt Miller, Lead Data Scientist; and Keith Shepherd, Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science. The webinar was chaired by Achim Dobermann, Chief Scientist at IFA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AfCPA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="notes-from-the-first-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture-8supthsup-to-10supthsup-december-2020">Notes from the first African Conference on Precision Agriculture, 8&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> to 10&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> December 2020.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The session was hosted by Jonathan Crouch (CEO, iSDA) with contributions from Matt Miller (Lead Data Scientist, iSDA), Jamie Collinson (CTO, iSDA), and Keith Shepherd (Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science, iSDA). The Panel comprised Praveen Singh (Agronomist, Indorama), Pieter Pypers (Senior Agronomist, International Institute of Tropical Agriculture), and Rik van den Bosch (Director, International Soil Reference and Information Centre).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>University of Aberdeen’s research project to tackle land loss in Ethiopia, utilises iSDAsoil</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</guid><description>&lt;p>David McBey and Michael Martin from the University of Aberdeen speak to iSDA about how they are using the iSDAsoil resource to underpin the tools developed for their project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project – &lt;a href="https://www.abdn.ac.uk/news/14502/">&lt;em>Reducing land degradation and carbon loss from Ethiopia’s soils to strengthen livelihoods and resilience&lt;/em>&lt;/a> – is funded through a £1,000,000 grant from the &lt;a href="https://www.ukri.org/our-work/collaborating-internationally/global-challenges-research-fund/">UKRI Global Challenges Research Fund (GCRF)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
 
 

 
 

 &lt;img 
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu1142662468807884024.png" 
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu2678322716574340148.png 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu1142662468807884024.png 1x"
 class="img-fluid">
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="david-mcbey-describes-the-project-aims-and-background">David McBey describes the project aims and background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My background is that I’m a social scientist. I’m employed on this project as an environmental modeller. We’re most interested in Ethiopia, because there’s a lot of degraded land there. I think it is about a quarter of the land, which impacts about a third of the population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ASA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Notes from the Special symposium on Translating Visionary Science for Excellence in African Agronomy at The American Society of Agronomy (ASA), the Crop Science Society of America (CSSA), and the Soil Science Society of America (SSSA) International Annual Meeting. 10th to 11th November 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/">View the recorded videos from the conference.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="african-soils-at-30-m-resolution-a-breakthrough-for-low-cost-agronomic-advisory">African soils at 30-m resolution. A breakthrough for low-cost agronomic advisory.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Presented by &lt;strong>Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong>. Chief Scientist, International Fertiliser Association.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Launch</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil">iSDAsoil&lt;/a> previously launched on 23&lt;sup>rd&lt;/sup> October 2020 and is an open access soil property map with 30m resolution for Africa. iSDA has collaborated with &lt;a href="https://www.worldagroforestry.org/">ICRAF&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.rothamsted.ac.uk/">Rothamsted Research&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://envirometrix.nl/">Envirometrix&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://gilab.rs/">GiLab&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://multione.hr/home.html">MultiOne&lt;/a> to gather the immense dataset which underpins this work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using on-site soil samples and computer modelling, a detailed and interactive image is produced displaying multiple properties of the soil throughout Africa. The high resolution of the data (24 billion data points) means that a single farm can identify the soil type accurate to a particular field. iSDAsoil also takes into account the depth of soil and the type of underlying bedrock to predict the full picture of soil status across the country. Where there are data gaps, iSDAsoil will be improved upon with further data received from dedicated soil agronomists.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>International Fertilizer Association Webinar 26 February 2021</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-information-revolution-in-africa-introducing-isdasoil">An information revolution in Africa? Introducing iSDAsoil&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="26-february-2021-3pm-to-4pm-cet">26 February 2021, 3pm to 4pm CET&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IFA, the International Fertilizer Association is holding a &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_UwuVtU-VTziZIJ1MTUtQlg">free webinar&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> focusing on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil&lt;/a>. IFA’s Members include fertilizer producers, traders and distributors, as well as their associations, service providers to the industry, research organizations, and non-governmental organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for a live demonstration of iSDAsoil with the team, and a discussion with &lt;strong>IFA Chief Scientist Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong> on what this mapping can mean for the future of farming in Africa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the AfCPA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p>To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil&lt;/a>, the iSDA team made two presentations at The 1st African Conference on Precision Agriculture (AfCPA) in December 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="an-introduction-to-isdasoil">An introduction to iSDAsoil&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Jonathan Crouch, CEO of iSDA presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the history of digital soil mapping in Africa, the improvements made in iSDAsoil, and some applications of the resource:&lt;/p>


 
 &lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MgX3tmDtbps?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
 >&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="the-isdasoil-interactive-workshop">The iSDAsoil interactive workshop&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The iSDA team then held an in-depth interactive session on iSDAsoil. This consisted of a live demo of iSDAsoil’s functionality, an expert panel discussion, and Q&amp;amp;A. The panel discussion members were:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the ASA-CSSA-SSSA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</guid><description>&lt;p>To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil&lt;/a>, the iSDA team made two presentations at The American Society of Agronomy, the Crop Science Society of America, and the Soil Science Society of America (ASA-CSSA-SSSA) Conference. This international virtual conference ran from the 9-13 November 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Achim Dobermann of the iSDA Board presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the problem space, importance of the breakthrough, and its potential applications:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>

 
 &lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EWbosAsGvGE?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
 >&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;em>Achim Dobermann presents iSDAsoil&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>