<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual_agronomist on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/virtual_agronomist/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual_agronomist on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 10:47:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/virtual_agronomist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>17 Crops Now Supported by AI Virtual Agronomist Across All African Countries</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/17-crops-for-all-countries-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 10:47:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/17-crops-for-all-countries-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>Smallholder farmers across Africa can now access tailored advisory services for 17 different crops through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI platform&lt;/a>, reflecting the growing demand from those who have already benefited from the system. With over 100,000 farmers using our service, many have experienced its value and are eager to extend its benefits to more crops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In response, our team has continuously expanded the crop offerings to better support farmers’ diverse needs. These updates to our service enable farmers, agribusinesses, and organisations to receive personalised, location-specific recommendations to enhance yields, increase profits and improve soil health across the continent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Delivers 100,000 Tailored Advisories to African Smallholder Farmers in the First Year</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to share that iSDA’s &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> has helped African farmers on over 100,000 plots - a fantastic milestone achieved in just one year since the launch of the AI expert advisory in February 2024! This achievement is more than a number - it is real impact. Thousands of farmers are now equipped with AI-powered, data-driven insights which helps them to instantaneously know their soil status (NPK values) and get a nutrient plan to adopt sustainable farming practices, improve their yields and increase their income.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unveiling the Impact of iSDA's Rice Harvest Data Survey in Mwea, Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/unveiling-the-impact-of-isda-rice-harvest-data-survey-in-mwea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:16:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/unveiling-the-impact-of-isda-rice-harvest-data-survey-in-mwea/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rice production is central to Mwea’s agricultural identity, contributing significantly to Kenya’s food security and economy while supporting thousands of smallholder farmers. However, challenges such as resource inefficiencies, soil degradation, and the need for precise farming practices make it difficult to meet growing demands sustainably.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To tackle these issues, our team at iSDA conducted a retrospective cohort study to assess the impact of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> compared with normal Farmer Practice in the Mwea Rice Scheme in Kenya. Designed to deliver tailored, data-driven recommendations, our Virtual Agronomist advisory service aims to enhance farming practices and boost productivity for farmers across Africa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024 in Review: Celebrating a Year of Milestones and Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2024 comes to an end, our team at iSDA are proud to look back on a year marked by progress, innovation, and meaningful impact. This year has been a significant step forward in our mission to transform smallholder farming across Africa through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a>, empowering farmers with tailored, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From expanding our reach to enhancing the accuracy of our AI-driven advice, we have seen firsthand how Virtual Agronomist can support sustainable farming practices, improve yields, and unlock potential for communities that rely on agriculture.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist at the CPCN Seminar: Revolutionising Agronomic Advice for Farmers Across Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a world where smallholder farmers face increasing challenges in achieving sustainable productivity, technology has emerged as a powerful ally. At the recent CPCN seminar, our innovative &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> took center stage. This cutting-edge tool delivers personalised agronomic advice directly to farmers via WhatsApp, bridging the gap between scientific insights and on-the-ground farming practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net">Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition (CPCN)&lt;/a> seminar is coordinated by Dr Canon Engoke, Senior Scientist at the &lt;a href="https://www.apni.net">African Plant Nutrition Institute&lt;/a> based in Nairobi, Kenya. The CPCN serves as a dynamic platform where companies, research institutes, universities, NGOs, and national programs collaborate to share expertise and data. It fosters the co-creation of aligned crop nutrition principles, standards, algorithms, and other vital resources. The seminar provides a hub for innovation, aiming to accelerate the development of effective, evidence-based digital crop nutrition advisory solutions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist Featured by Voice of America: Transforming Farming in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we are committed to revolutionising agriculture across Africa by empowering farmers with valuable agronomic knowledge. Our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual_agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory service&lt;/a> is designed to equip farmers with actionable insights tailored to their unique needs. Recent testimonials from Mwea, Kenya, where rice farming thrives, reveal the profound impact of this technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohammed Yusuf from &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com">Voice of America&lt;/a> recently visited farmers in Mwea, including Henry Gichobi, who shared how Virtual Agronomist has transformed his approach to farming. By leveraging Virtual Agronomist’s AI-driven analysis, Henry now makes data-informed decisions about fertilisers and chemicals, resulting in a dramatic increase in yield. &amp;ldquo;Before this technology, I was harvesting less than 20 bags. Now, I harvest 26 bags and above,&amp;rdquo; he said. With precise satellite imagery and soil nutrient data, Henry receives recommendations that maximise his productivity while reducing unnecessary input costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA &amp; IAPRI Release Empowering Documentary</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-iapri-collaborate-for-documentary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-iapri-collaborate-for-documentary/</guid><description>&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oiQUzPH6ASE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="our-collaboration-with-iapri">&lt;strong>Our Collaboration with IAPRI&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>At iSDA, we’re excited to work alongside the Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute (IAPRI) to promote our innovative Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service. Initially, IAPRI used local media to reach farmers in the pilot districts of Kapiri-Mposhi and Monze in Zambia through community radio. However, as interest grew, they decided to scale the outreach to a national level. This led them to partner with the Zambian National Broadcasting Corporation (ZNBC) to create a documentary that highlights the benefits of Virtual Agronomist’s AI technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stories From the Field: A Female Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:16:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/stories-from-the-field-a-female-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the global agricultural landscape evolves, the role of women in farming is increasingly recognised as a vital force for sustainable development. In our “Stories from the Field” series, we seek to highlight the experiences of our farmers and agronomists across Africa. This article focuses on some of the women in Uganda who leverage &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> to enhance their agricultural practices, boost their maize yields, and improve their quality of life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Update: Our New Image-Based Pest and Disease Feature</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:26:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we are proud of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> service and its ability to improve farmers&amp;rsquo; crop yield and soil health. Our service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers on WhatsApp, giving them personalized nutrient plans and essential agronomic advice for their crops and soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtual Agronomist offers farmers &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/">many helpful agronomic services&lt;/a>, including a diagnostic pest and disease feature that asks farmers questions about their plants&amp;rsquo; growth and any issues they notice that concern them, for example, insect larvae, lesions, leaf discoloration, or head smut. The information is then processed by our scientific model, which provides a likely diagnosis and suggests treatments. It can also estimate the potential impact on crop yields if the issue is not managed properly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist: Feature Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:25:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our new generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other essential agronomic advice for their plots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far, &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/">we have launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for maize and rice&lt;/a>. Additionally, preparations are underway to launch Virtual Agronomist in Zambia for maize crops within the next few months. Virtual Agronomist supports the farmer with tailored advice throughout the season and can prompt and remind them of vital agronomic operations, for example, field mapping, soil data for their field, tailored nutrient plans, checking crop emergence, scouting for weeds, pests, and diseases, and harvesting. Through the features of our Virtual Agronomist service, farmers have the tools and advice they need to improve their crop health, yields and profits through better agronomic management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International. Using Virtual Agronomist, our tailored advisory service, the Field Technicians generated specific nutrient recommendations for each farmer along with suggestions to improve agronomic practices. We demonstrated that the prospective yield and profit results with Virtual Agronomist were on average three times the farmer’s previous practice, when accompanied by good agronomic management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sustain Africa - increasing access to affordable fertiliser at scale</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>As fertiliser prices continued to spike due to the Russia/Ukraine conflict, iSDA joined the &lt;a href="https://sustainafrica-initiative.org">Sustain Africa&lt;/a> initiative in 2022 to increase African farmers&amp;rsquo; access to affordable fertiliser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A great challenge when it comes to fertiliser use in Africa is the lack of precision in delivering the correct chemical formulation needed for each patch of farmland. Not all soils are formed or managed equally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>iSDA&amp;rsquo;s role in the Sustain Africa initiative has therefore been to deploy our app &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a> to tackle this issue. The system was created to provide individual farmers in Africa, who usually do not have access to lab testing, the ability to assess the soil properties of their farmland and provide nutrient management plans for sustainable increases in crop yield.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grow-nourish-reward---bold-actions-for-resilient-food-systems">Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://agrf.org/AGRFSummit/">AGRF&lt;/a>, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
 
 

 
 

 &lt;img 
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_79d32a3db560fdb0.webp" 
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_8689c25d3c9fe67b.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_79d32a3db560fdb0.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="virtual-agronomist">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Directly supporting the aims of the summit is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist">Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a>, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA introduces the Virtual Agronomist App to the International Fertiliser Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 26&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> February 2021 the iSDA team demonstrated the &lt;strong>prototype app “Virtual Agronomist”&lt;/strong> to the International Fertilizer Association (IFA). &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8GyxpSyeWs">The recorded webinar is available to view on YouTube.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presenting and answering the many user questions were members of the iSDA team: Jonathan Crouch, CEO; Jamie Collinson, CTO; Monica Cross, Head of Operations; Matt Miller, Lead Data Scientist; and Keith Shepherd, Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science. The webinar was chaired by Achim Dobermann, Chief Scientist at IFA.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>