<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual_agronomist on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/virtual_agronomist/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual_agronomist on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/virtual_agronomist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Virtual Agronomist Detected Downy Mildew in Malawi Before the Official Outbreak</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/how-virtual-agronomist-detected-downy-mildew-in-malawi-before-the-official-outbreak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/how-virtual-agronomist-detected-downy-mildew-in-malawi-before-the-official-outbreak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-moving world of agriculture, timing is everything. A few days can mean the difference between a healthy harvest and devastating crop loss. This is the story of how one farmer used Virtual Agronomist to detect a disease outbreak before government authorities even announced it. This is the proof that AI-powered agronomy isn&amp;rsquo;t just convenient; it&amp;rsquo;s transformative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During one of his usual morning inspections on his small maize field in Lilongwe, Malawi, Paul Chunga noticed something troubling on his leaves. He pulled out his phone, opened WhatsApp, and messaged Virtual Agronomist. Within minutes, he had his answer: &lt;strong&gt;Downy Mildew.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Supporting Healthy Soils for Healthy Cities: Virtual Agronomist's Role in Urban and Peri-Urban Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 marks the United Nations World Soil Day (WSD). This year&amp;rsquo;s theme, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Healthy soils for healthy cities,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; highlights the critical role of soils in urban areas. Healthy urban soils filter water, store carbon, regulate temperatures, support biodiversity and even sustain food production. With two-thirds of the world&amp;rsquo;s population expected to live in cities by 2050, there is an urgent need for a one health approach across urban spaces to sustain and restore the health of our soils, the health of our cities, ecosystems and people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA's Chief Scientist Dr. Keith Shepherd Wins 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-ifa-25/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rabat, Morocco – November 19, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; – iSDA is proud to announce that Dr. Keith Shepherd, Chief Scientist, has been awarded the 2025 IFA Norman Borlaug Plant Nutrition Award. The award was presented yesterday during the IFA Strategic Forum in Rabat, Morocco, recognizing Dr. Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s contributions to plant nutrition research and sustainable agricultural development across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-testament-to-scientific-excellence-and-real-world-impact"&gt;A Testament to Scientific Excellence and Real-World Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shepherd was selected by the Scientific Panel on Responsible Plant Nutrition (SPRPN). The panel was particularly impressed by the clarity of achievements from his research, which spans from significant scientific innovation to large-scale, tangible impact on the ground, delivering solutions that directly benefit smallholder farmers across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA at COP30: Bringing Africa's Climate-Ready Farmers to the Global Stage</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-at-cop30-bringing-africas-climate-ready-farmers-to-the-global-stage/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="belém-brazil--november-12-14-2025"&gt;Belém, Brazil | November 12-14, 2025&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in our history, Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (iSDA) took our place at COP30, the world&amp;rsquo;s most important climate conference. As delegates from nearly 200 countries gathered in Belém, Brazil, at the very edge of the Amazon rainforest, we delivered a powerful message: building climate resilience for Africa&amp;rsquo;s smallholder farmers isn&amp;rsquo;t a future promise. It needs to happen now, at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One Youth Farmer, 15,000 Others Inspired</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/amos-spotlight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:48:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/amos-spotlight/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, digital agriculture is reshaping how young people see farming. Drones, climate apps, mobile advisory platforms are making agriculture look cool, profitable and modern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s working: the majority of digital agriculture users in Africa are aged 15–35, showing how technology is pulling a new generation back to farming. From Hello Tractor in Nigeria to DigiFarm in Kenya, young people are driving adoption. Projects like Hinga Weze in Rwanda and startups like M-Omulimisa in Uganda are proving the same thing: give youth the right tools, and they transform agriculture into a business worth staying in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Reaches 250,000 Farmers: Scaling Real Solutions, Fast</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/250000-unique-farmers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:38:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/250000-unique-farmers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just one month ago, we announced that Virtual Agronomist had reached more than 250,000 farm plots with locally tailored, AI-powered advice. Today, that figure already looks out of date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve now passed 350,000 farm plots, and for the first time, we can say we are directly serving a quarter of a million farmers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more than a milestone. It’s evidence of huge, rapid growth — and of the power of a model that is working at scale, and in reality, for African farmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Last Mile, First Priority: What It Takes to Get Tech to the Field</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/last-mile-first-priority-monalisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 13:04:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/last-mile-first-priority-monalisa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Q&amp;amp;A with Monalisa Mutesi, iSDA’s Uganda Country Director&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The last mile is where change takes root. If you care about scale, you have to get your hands dirty and your boots muddy.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monalisa Mutesi is the driving force behind iSDA’s work in Uganda — and a firm believer that the best agtech means nothing if it doesn’t work for farmers on the ground. As Uganda Country Director, she leads iSDA’s last-mile delivery work: connecting science to farmers, turning insights into impact and building partnerships that make scale real.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beyond the Harvest: How Virtual Agronomist Is Doing More Than Improving Yields</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/doing-more-than-improving-yields/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:04:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/doing-more-than-improving-yields/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Last year’s income was quite high, so I decided to build a good house for me to live in, and this is what I am working on finalising.”&lt;/em&gt;
— Dorcas Macharia, smallholder farmer, Reru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, smallholder farmers face mounting challenges - unpredictable weather, rising input costs and limited access to expert guidance.
But change is underway, driven by a new generation of science-backed tools like iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-virtual-agronomist-works"&gt;How Virtual Agronomist Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Agronomist delivers personalised, expert advice via WhatsApp, tailored to each farmer’s soil,
crop and weather conditions. It guides decisions on fertiliser use, pest control and planting schedules - combining local data with cutting-edge science.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What If Every Farmer Could Diagnose Their Soil? Now They Can</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/know-your-soil-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 10:10:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/know-your-soil-release/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Despite extensive scientific effort in creating soil maps, they seldom reach farmers in a usable form.
Know Your Soil changes that by delivering tailored summaries of soil constraints for each field, together with clear, actionable management recommendations.
Farmers are also guided through simple on-farm observations to identify more subtle issues - such as structural limitations - and adapt their practices accordingly.
Accessible via WhatsApp through Virtual Agronomist, Know Your Soil serves as a practical learning resource for both farmers and extension agents.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Advice in Action: Virtual Agronomist Delivers Higher Yields for Ugandan Sunflower Farmers</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/uganda-sunflower-farmers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:33:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/uganda-sunflower-farmers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Uganda’s agricultural sector plays a vital role in driving economic growth, reducing poverty and ensuring national food security.
Contributing around 24% to GDP and employing over 70% of the population, agriculture is the country’s economic backbone.
Yet with most farming rain-fed and subsistence-based, the sector remains highly vulnerable to climate change - especially to increasingly frequent and severe droughts.
By 2050, climate impacts are projected to cause economic losses of up to US$1.5 billion for smallholder farmers across Africa. Their livelihoods - and national food systems - are under growing threat.
That’s why iSDA is building tools that combine world-class science with cutting-edge technology to help farmers adapt.
At the centre of this work is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist (VA)&lt;/a&gt; - our AI-powered advisory tool, delivered via WhatsApp, that provides data-driven,
hyper-local advice to farmers across Africa. What makes VA different is its foundation in science: it generates fertiliser and nutrient management plans tailored to individual plots,
using high-resolution soil data from &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s most detailed soil mapping platform. By pairing soil diagnostics with real-time insights on pests, disease and weather,
Virtual Agronomist helps farmers make smarter decisions - boosting productivity and building resilience to climate shocks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why the Next Generation of Farm Advisory Needs More Than Just Cool Tech</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-the-next-generation-of-farm-advisory-needs-more-than-just-cool-tech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:58:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/why-the-next-generation-of-farm-advisory-needs-more-than-just-cool-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Africa, millions of farmers face a fundamental challenge: they lack access to timely, tailored advice that can help them make confident decisions about their crops and soils.
This isn’t a new problem. What’s new is the tools at our disposal to solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we believe the future of farm advisory is more than just tech. It’s about trust, science, systems - and scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-more-tech-doesnt-automatically-mean-better-advice"&gt;1. More Tech Doesn’t Automatically Mean Better Advice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, we’ve seen a surge in AI-powered platforms promising to revolutionise smallholder agriculture. And yes - technology is unlocking new possibilities. But when tech is deployed without a deep understanding of agronomy, local context or farmer realities, it risks repeating old mistakes in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building Virtual Agronomist: Notes from a Kenyan Software Engineer</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/notes-from-a-kenyan-software-engineer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 11:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/notes-from-a-kenyan-software-engineer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Meet Abi Wairimu, one of the brilliant minds behind Virtual Agronomist. Her
journey began with a passion for computer science and a belief that technology could
transform African agriculture and has led her to playing an instrumental part in
bringing Virtual Agronomist to life. Here she shares how combining AI, science and
farmer insights has created a tool that’s as much about people as it is about tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-first-drew-you-to-this-work"&gt;What first drew you to this work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started studying computer science, I was fascinated by the potential of
AI systems and how they could be applied to solve real-world problems. So when I had
the chance to help build Virtual Agronomist, I jumped at it. It brings together
machine learning, expert systems and generative AI - but what excites me most is
that it’s already delivering tangible value to farmers across Africa.
This isn’t just a lab experiment - it’s AI at work in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>200,000 Plots and Counting: Celebrating One Year of Our Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory Service</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In its first year, our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has provided tailored nutrient recommendations for over 200,000 farm plots across Africa. This confirms our mission to empower African farmers with easy-to-access tailored, data-driven insights to enhance productivity, profitability, sustainability, and decision-making. Using our extensive knowledge base, &lt;a href="isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; soil analysis, and advisory engine, our service is designed to provide instant, personalised guidance throughout the farming season — helping farmers optimise crop health, manage resources efficiently, and navigate climate challenges with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>17 Crops Now Supported by AI Virtual Agronomist Across All African Countries</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/17-crops-for-all-countries-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 10:47:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/17-crops-for-all-countries-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Smallholder farmers across Africa can now access tailored advisory services for 17 different crops through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI platform&lt;/a&gt;, reflecting the growing demand from those who have already benefited from the system. With over 100,000 farmers using our service, many have experienced its value and are eager to extend its benefits to more crops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, our team has continuously expanded the crop offerings to better support farmers’ diverse needs. These updates to our service enable farmers, agribusinesses, and organisations to receive personalised, location-specific recommendations to enhance yields, increase profits and improve soil health across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Delivers 100,000 Tailored Advisories to African Smallholder Farmers in the First Year</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/100000-plots-milestone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to share that iSDA’s &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has helped African farmers on over 100,000 plots - a fantastic milestone achieved in just one year since the launch of the AI expert advisory in February 2024! This achievement is more than a number - it is real impact. Thousands of farmers are now equipped with AI-powered, data-driven insights which helps them to instantaneously know their soil status (NPK values) and get a nutrient plan to adopt sustainable farming practices, improve their yields and increase their income.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2024 in Review: Celebrating a Year of Milestones and Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2024 comes to an end, our team at iSDA are proud to look back on a year marked by progress, innovation, and meaningful impact. This year has been a significant step forward in our mission to transform smallholder farming across Africa through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;, empowering farmers with tailored, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From expanding our reach to enhancing the accuracy of our AI-driven advice, we have seen firsthand how Virtual Agronomist can support sustainable farming practices, improve yields, and unlock potential for communities that rely on agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist at the CPCN Seminar: Revolutionising Agronomic Advice for Farmers Across Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-at-cpcn-seminar-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where smallholder farmers face increasing challenges in achieving sustainable productivity, technology has emerged as a powerful ally. At the recent CPCN seminar, our innovative &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; took center stage. This cutting-edge tool delivers personalised agronomic advice directly to farmers via WhatsApp, bridging the gap between scientific insights and on-the-ground farming practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.precisioncropnutrition.net"&gt;Consortium for Precision Crop Nutrition (CPCN)&lt;/a&gt; seminar is coordinated by Dr Canon Engoke, Senior Scientist at the &lt;a href="https://www.apni.net"&gt;African Plant Nutrition Institute&lt;/a&gt; based in Nairobi, Kenya. The CPCN serves as a dynamic platform where companies, research institutes, universities, NGOs, and national programs collaborate to share expertise and data. It fosters the co-creation of aligned crop nutrition principles, standards, algorithms, and other vital resources. The seminar provides a hub for innovation, aiming to accelerate the development of effective, evidence-based digital crop nutrition advisory solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist Update: Our New Image-Based Pest and Disease Feature</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 19:26:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/new-image-based-pest-and-disease-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we are proud of our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; service and its ability to improve farmers&amp;rsquo; crop yield and soil health. Our service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers on WhatsApp, giving them personalized nutrient plans and essential agronomic advice for their crops and soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Agronomist offers farmers &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/"&gt;many helpful agronomic services&lt;/a&gt;, including a diagnostic pest and disease feature that asks farmers questions about their plants&amp;rsquo; growth and any issues they notice that concern them, for example, insect larvae, lesions, leaf discoloration, or head smut. The information is then processed by our scientific model, which provides a likely diagnosis and suggests treatments. It can also estimate the potential impact on crop yields if the issue is not managed properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Virtual Agronomist: Feature Focus</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:25:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-feature-focus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Our new generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; service uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other essential agronomic advice for their plots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/"&gt;we have launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for maize and rice&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, preparations are underway to launch Virtual Agronomist in Zambia for maize crops within the next few months. Virtual Agronomist supports the farmer with tailored advice throughout the season and can prompt and remind them of vital agronomic operations, for example, field mapping, soil data for their field, tailored nutrient plans, checking crop emergence, scouting for weeds, pests, and diseases, and harvesting. Through the features of our Virtual Agronomist service, farmers have the tools and advice they need to improve their crop health, yields and profits through better agronomic management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Times More Yield for Tanzanian Farmers With Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/tanzania-three-times-more-yield/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we have been seeing fantastic positive yield responses with &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; across a range of crops and countries, including maize in Côte D’Ivoire, barley and sorghum in Uganda, coffee in Kenya and rice in Zambia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most notable responses comes from sunflower and rice farmers in Tanzania whose crops are showing impressive yield results and offering positive predictions in growth and profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022 we started a pilot programme in Tanzania with sunflower farmers in Singida, Iringa, Manyara and Dodoma with Pyxus International. Using Virtual Agronomist, our tailored advisory service, the Field Technicians generated specific nutrient recommendations for each farmer along with suggestions to improve agronomic practices. We demonstrated that the prospective yield and profit results with Virtual Agronomist were on average three times the farmer’s previous practice, when accompanied by good agronomic management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sustain Africa - increasing access to affordable fertiliser at scale</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As fertiliser prices continued to spike due to the Russia/Ukraine conflict, iSDA joined the &lt;a href="https://sustainafrica-initiative.org"&gt;Sustain Africa&lt;/a&gt; initiative in 2022 to increase African farmers&amp;rsquo; access to affordable fertiliser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great challenge when it comes to fertiliser use in Africa is the lack of precision in delivering the correct chemical formulation needed for each patch of farmland. Not all soils are formed or managed equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iSDA&amp;rsquo;s role in the Sustain Africa initiative has therefore been to deploy our app &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; to tackle this issue. The system was created to provide individual farmers in Africa, who usually do not have access to lab testing, the ability to assess the soil properties of their farmland and provide nutrient management plans for sustainable increases in crop yield.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grow-nourish-reward---bold-actions-for-resilient-food-systems"&gt;Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://agrf.org/AGRFSummit/"&gt;AGRF&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_7d726292839b79a2.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_43bdc567e031fb0b.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_7d726292839b79a2.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directly supporting the aims of the summit is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA introduces the Virtual Agronomist App to the International Fertiliser Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February 2021 the iSDA team demonstrated the &lt;strong&gt;prototype app “Virtual Agronomist”&lt;/strong&gt; to the International Fertilizer Association (IFA). &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8GyxpSyeWs"&gt;The recorded webinar is available to view on YouTube.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting and answering the many user questions were members of the iSDA team: Jonathan Crouch, CEO; Jamie Collinson, CTO; Monica Cross, Head of Operations; Matt Miller, Lead Data Scientist; and Keith Shepherd, Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science. The webinar was chaired by Achim Dobermann, Chief Scientist at IFA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>