<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Partnerships on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/partnerships/</link><description>Recent content in Partnerships on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/partnerships/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Better Futures: Our Partnership With OMMA Ltd.</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/building-better-futures-our-partnership-with-omma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/building-better-futures-our-partnership-with-omma/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we pride ourselves on using cutting-edge agricultural technologies to empower farmers and improve livelihoods. It is with great enthusiasm that we announce our partnership with OMMA Ltd, a unique ecosystem that enhances food security, promotes sustainability, and stimulates economic growth, based in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This collaboration marks a significant step forward in delivering precision agriculture tools directly to those who need them most: smallholder maize and rice farmers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empowering Farmers in Uganda: Our New Partnership with Ecolife</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-announces-partnership-with-ecolife/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:26:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-announces-partnership-with-ecolife/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we believe that data-driven solutions can transform agriculture, especially when combined with local expertise and on-the-ground support. We are thrilled to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.ecolifefoods.org/">Ecolife&lt;/a> in Kitula-Namayumba, Uganda, aimed at launching our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> for 1,000 maize farmers. This initiative, which began in September 2024, is focused on driving improved yield, quality, and profitability for local farmers while supporting Ecolife’s mission of sustainable agricultural growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA Africa Announces Exciting Partnership With Niger Foods</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-working-in-partnership-with-niger-foods-to-revolutionise-agriculture-with-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 15:16:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-africa-working-in-partnership-with-niger-foods-to-revolutionise-agriculture-with-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a significant step towards transforming agriculture in Nigeria, we are excited to announce a groundbreaking partnership with &lt;a href="https://nigerfoods.com">Niger Foods&lt;/a> to deliver AI-powered advisory services to farmers in the Niger State!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of this partnership, we will deploy our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a> to provide maize, soybean, and rice farmers with real-time, data-driven insights and advice to enhance crop management and increase yields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our service will provide personalised recommendations for essential agricultural practices, including fertiliser application and pest control, tailored to the unique conditions of each farm and will assist the farmers in improving their soil health by identifying nutritional deficiencies and suggesting the application of the correct nutrient balance.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>