<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Media on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/media/</link><description>Recent content in Media on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:36:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA’s Virtual Agronomist Featured by Voice of America: Transforming Farming in Kenya</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-featured-voice-of-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>At iSDA, we are committed to revolutionising agriculture across Africa by empowering farmers with valuable agronomic knowledge. Our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual_agronomist/">Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory service&lt;/a> is designed to equip farmers with actionable insights tailored to their unique needs. Recent testimonials from Mwea, Kenya, where rice farming thrives, reveal the profound impact of this technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohammed Yusuf from &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com">Voice of America&lt;/a> recently visited farmers in Mwea, including Henry Gichobi, who shared how Virtual Agronomist has transformed his approach to farming. By leveraging Virtual Agronomist’s AI-driven analysis, Henry now makes data-informed decisions about fertilisers and chemicals, resulting in a dramatic increase in yield. &amp;ldquo;Before this technology, I was harvesting less than 20 bags. Now, I harvest 26 bags and above,&amp;rdquo; he said. With precise satellite imagery and soil nutrient data, Henry receives recommendations that maximise his productivity while reducing unnecessary input costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDA &amp; IAPRI Release Empowering Documentary</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-iapri-collaborate-for-documentary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-and-iapri-collaborate-for-documentary/</guid><description>&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oiQUzPH6ASE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="our-collaboration-with-iapri">&lt;strong>Our Collaboration with IAPRI&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>At iSDA, we’re excited to work alongside the Indaba Agricultural Policy Research Institute (IAPRI) to promote our innovative Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service. Initially, IAPRI used local media to reach farmers in the pilot districts of Kapiri-Mposhi and Monze in Zambia through community radio. However, as interest grew, they decided to scale the outreach to a national level. This led them to partner with the Zambian National Broadcasting Corporation (ZNBC) to create a documentary that highlights the benefits of Virtual Agronomist’s AI technology.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>