<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Company on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/company/</link><description>Recent content in Company on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:36:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/company/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA Announces New Board Member: Mr Richard Sears</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/announcing-our-new-board-member-richard-sears/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:36:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/announcing-our-new-board-member-richard-sears/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the appointment of Mr Richard Sears to the iSDA Board of Directors. With a diverse career spanning across multiple sectors including technology, finance and non-profit work, Richard is an accomplished entrepreneur and investor. His extensive global experience covers regions such as Europe, Africa, Asia, and South America, where he has successfully launched multiple ventures, non-profits, and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="our-new-board-member"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our New Board Member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard currently serves as Investment Director at Kuvi Capital, where he leads venture and private equity investments, managing a portfolio of 25 companies across Europe, Africa, and the U.S. Prior to this, he played a key role as Head of Ventures at The Baobab Network, an accelerator supporting early-stage African tech companies. His work has empowered over 25 start-ups across 11 African countries, in partnership with global investors and corporations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CEO Announcement</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-08-ceo-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-08-ceo-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the iSDA Board and team, I am delighted to announce Jamie Collinson as our new Chief Executive Officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jamie has been instrumental to iSDA’s development since joining as Chief Technology Officer in 2020. His appointment to CEO reflects our firm belief, demonstrated over iSDA&amp;rsquo;s initial discovery phase, that a technology and science-driven approach will unlock agricultural productivity across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jamie is a world-class technologist, and has a demonstrated track record of growing early stage businesses to success. I have every confidence that his skills and leadership will take iSDA through our next phase of maturity into industry leadership, and accelerate our mission to bring individually tailored advice to millions of farmers across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>