<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/categories/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDA introduces the Virtual Agronomist App to the International Fertiliser Association</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:36:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-isda-introduces-virtual-agronomist-app-to-ifa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February 2021 the iSDA team demonstrated the &lt;strong&gt;prototype app “Virtual Agronomist”&lt;/strong&gt; to the International Fertilizer Association (IFA). &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8GyxpSyeWs"&gt;The recorded webinar is available to view on YouTube.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting and answering the many user questions were members of the iSDA team: Jonathan Crouch, CEO; Jamie Collinson, CTO; Monica Cross, Head of Operations; Matt Miller, Lead Data Scientist; and Keith Shepherd, Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science. The webinar was chaired by Achim Dobermann, Chief Scientist at IFA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AfCPA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="notes-from-the-first-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture-8th-to-10th-december-2020"&gt;Notes from the first African Conference on Precision Agriculture, 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December 2020.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session was hosted by Jonathan Crouch (CEO, iSDA) with contributions from Matt Miller (Lead Data Scientist, iSDA), Jamie Collinson (CTO, iSDA), and Keith Shepherd (Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science, iSDA). The Panel comprised Praveen Singh (Agronomist, Indorama), Pieter Pypers (Senior Agronomist, International Institute of Tropical Agriculture), and Rik van den Bosch (Director, International Soil Reference and Information Centre).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>University of Aberdeen’s research project to tackle land loss in Ethiopia, utilises iSDAsoil</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;David McBey and Michael Martin from the University of Aberdeen speak to iSDA about how they are using the iSDAsoil resource to underpin the tools developed for their project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project – &lt;a href="https://www.abdn.ac.uk/news/14502/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reducing land degradation and carbon loss from Ethiopia’s soils to strengthen livelihoods and resilience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – is funded through a £1,000,000 grant from the &lt;a href="https://www.ukri.org/our-work/collaborating-internationally/global-challenges-research-fund/"&gt;UKRI Global Challenges Research Fund (GCRF)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_9d1e76cc6d8a0ca2.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_acc0548fdbebbfe4.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_9d1e76cc6d8a0ca2.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="david-mcbey-describes-the-project-aims-and-background"&gt;David McBey describes the project aims and background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My background is that I’m a social scientist. I’m employed on this project as an environmental modeller. We’re most interested in Ethiopia, because there’s a lot of degraded land there. I think it is about a quarter of the land, which impacts about a third of the population.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ASA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from the Special symposium on Translating Visionary Science for Excellence in African Agronomy at The American Society of Agronomy (ASA), the Crop Science Society of America (CSSA), and the Soil Science Society of America (SSSA) International Annual Meeting. 10th to 11th November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/"&gt;View the recorded videos from the conference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="african-soils-at-30-m-resolution-a-breakthrough-for-low-cost-agronomic-advisory"&gt;African soils at 30-m resolution. A breakthrough for low-cost agronomic advisory.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by &lt;strong&gt;Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt;. Chief Scientist, International Fertiliser Association.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Launch</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; previously launched on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; October 2020 and is an open access soil property map with 30m resolution for Africa. iSDA has collaborated with &lt;a href="https://www.worldagroforestry.org/"&gt;ICRAF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.rothamsted.ac.uk/"&gt;Rothamsted Research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://envirometrix.nl/"&gt;Envirometrix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gilab.rs/"&gt;GiLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://multione.hr/home.html"&gt;MultiOne&lt;/a&gt; to gather the immense dataset which underpins this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using on-site soil samples and computer modelling, a detailed and interactive image is produced displaying multiple properties of the soil throughout Africa. The high resolution of the data (24 billion data points) means that a single farm can identify the soil type accurate to a particular field. iSDAsoil also takes into account the depth of soil and the type of underlying bedrock to predict the full picture of soil status across the country. Where there are data gaps, iSDAsoil will be improved upon with further data received from dedicated soil agronomists.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>International Fertilizer Association Webinar 26 February 2021</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-information-revolution-in-africa-introducing-isdasoil"&gt;An information revolution in Africa? Introducing iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="26-february-2021-3pm-to-4pm-cet"&gt;26 February 2021, 3pm to 4pm CET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFA, the International Fertilizer Association is holding a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_UwuVtU-VTziZIJ1MTUtQlg"&gt;free webinar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focusing on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;. IFA’s Members include fertilizer producers, traders and distributors, as well as their associations, service providers to the industry, research organizations, and non-governmental organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for a live demonstration of iSDAsoil with the team, and a discussion with &lt;strong&gt;IFA Chief Scientist Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt; on what this mapping can mean for the future of farming in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>