<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iSDAsoil on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/</link><description>Recent content in iSDAsoil on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developer Portal</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-do-i-sign-up-to-use-the-isdasoil-api">How do I sign up to use the iSDAsoil API?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sign up by creating a username and password on our &lt;a href="https://isda-africa.com/api/registration">sign up page&lt;/a>. This
will be required to obtain an access token.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-can-i-do-with-the-isdasoil-api">What can I do with the iSDAsoil API?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our API will allow you to retrieve soil property and agronomy information for any location within Africa (excluding
water bodies and deserts) by providing values for latitude and longitude. Most of our layers are at 30m resolution,
except those provided by third parties. For further details on the available data, see our FAQ.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Technical Information</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/technical-information/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/technical-information/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-were-these-maps-made">How were these maps made?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hope it will give you a good understanding of the unique process we’ve developed to create our maps. For detailed information on our workflow, please read our paper in &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-85639-y">Nature Scientific Reports&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our key output is spatial predictions of crucial soil nutrients and properties, based on the predictive soil mapping (PSM) techniques. The first step in this process is to standardise all the input soil data by i) ensuring all measured units are in the same format; ii) harmonizing properties measured using different techniques; and iii) removing any erroneous datapoints.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil on the AWS Registry of Open Data</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/isdasoil-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/isdasoil-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains information about how to access the &lt;a href="https://registry.opendata.aws/isdasoil/">iSDAsoil data hosted on the AWS Registry of Open Data&lt;/a>, as well as background information about the dataset that will help you to use it. To visually explore the maps that we’ve created, please visit the &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil">iSDAsoil homepage&lt;/a>. You can find more detailed information on how the maps were made on our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/technical-information">technical information&lt;/a> and further information on our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/faq">FAQ&lt;/a> pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-overview">Data Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>All data has been prepared as cloud-optimised geoTIFFs (essentially geographically aware images). A single file covers the whole of Africa. Related data have been grouped together as bands in a single file. For most soil property predictions, this means that each file has 4 bands – the predicted mean value, and model error (expressed as 1 standard deviation) at 2 soil depths: 0-20cm and 20-50cm. For covariate data the number of bands is variable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open access soil data for Africa</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/open-soil-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/open-soil-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of our commitment to open access data, we are maintaining a soil analysis dataset for Africa. Our intention is to bring together as much soil data as possible in an analysis-ready format. We use this dataset to train the models that create the &lt;a href="https://isda-africa.com/isdasoil">iSDAsoil&lt;/a> maps. We plan to regularly update this resource with additional soil data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contributing-data">Contributing data&lt;/h2>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are maintaining a GitHub repository at &lt;a href="https://github.com/iSDA-Africa/open-soil-data">https://github.com/iSDA-Africa/open-soil-data&lt;/a>. We welcome any pull requests contributing additional data. Alternatively you can &lt;a href="mailto:info@isda-africa.com">get in touch via email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Terms of Use</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/terms/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-who-we-are-and-how-to-contact-us">1. Who we are and how to contact us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The soil maps and data presented within iSDAsoil (together “iSDAsoil”) are made available by Innovative Solutions for Decision Agriculture (“Us”). We are registered in England and Wales under company number 11429051 and have our registered office at Rothamsted Research, West Common, Harpenden, Hertfordshire, AL5 2JQ. We are a social enterprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-by-accessing-and-using-isdasoil-you-accept-these-terms">2. By accessing and using iSDAsoil you accept these terms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By accessing and using iSDAsoil, you confirm that you accept and agree to comply with: these terms, the general &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/terms-of-use/">Terms of Use&lt;/a>  governing our website and our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/privacy-policy/">Privacy and Cookie Policy&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>