<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ISDAsoil on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/isdasoil/</link><description>Recent content in ISDAsoil on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/isdasoil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iSDAsoil used in malaria mapping study</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;p>iSDA’s soil and agronomy map iSDAsoil was recently used by scientists to create a framework to map the malaria exposure levels of Africans living in towns and cities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though iSDAsoil is primarily used by iSDA as input for Virtual Agronomist, which determines the best use and combinations of fertilisers on their land, it also contains information on different chemical and physical soil properties that were used by these scientists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soil pH has an effect on the habitats of the Anopheles mosquito which transmits malaria. The scientists in this study therefore incorporated soil pH data to further determine the possible habitats of the mosquitoes. For this, they used open data from iSDAsoil at a depth of 0–20 cm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AfCPA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="notes-from-the-first-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture-8supthsup-to-10supthsup-december-2020">Notes from the first African Conference on Precision Agriculture, 8&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> to 10&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> December 2020.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The session was hosted by Jonathan Crouch (CEO, iSDA) with contributions from Matt Miller (Lead Data Scientist, iSDA), Jamie Collinson (CTO, iSDA), and Keith Shepherd (Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science, iSDA). The Panel comprised Praveen Singh (Agronomist, Indorama), Pieter Pypers (Senior Agronomist, International Institute of Tropical Agriculture), and Rik van den Bosch (Director, International Soil Reference and Information Centre).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>University of Aberdeen’s research project to tackle land loss in Ethiopia, utilises iSDAsoil</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</guid><description>&lt;p>David McBey and Michael Martin from the University of Aberdeen speak to iSDA about how they are using the iSDAsoil resource to underpin the tools developed for their project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project – &lt;a href="https://www.abdn.ac.uk/news/14502/">&lt;em>Reducing land degradation and carbon loss from Ethiopia’s soils to strengthen livelihoods and resilience&lt;/em>&lt;/a> – is funded through a £1,000,000 grant from the &lt;a href="https://www.ukri.org/our-work/collaborating-internationally/global-challenges-research-fund/">UKRI Global Challenges Research Fund (GCRF)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
 
 

 
 

 &lt;img 
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_9d1e76cc6d8a0ca2.webp" 
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_acc0548fdbebbfe4.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_9d1e76cc6d8a0ca2.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid">
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="david-mcbey-describes-the-project-aims-and-background">David McBey describes the project aims and background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My background is that I’m a social scientist. I’m employed on this project as an environmental modeller. We’re most interested in Ethiopia, because there’s a lot of degraded land there. I think it is about a quarter of the land, which impacts about a third of the population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ASA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Notes from the Special symposium on Translating Visionary Science for Excellence in African Agronomy at The American Society of Agronomy (ASA), the Crop Science Society of America (CSSA), and the Soil Science Society of America (SSSA) International Annual Meeting. 10th to 11th November 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/">View the recorded videos from the conference.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="african-soils-at-30-m-resolution-a-breakthrough-for-low-cost-agronomic-advisory">African soils at 30-m resolution. A breakthrough for low-cost agronomic advisory.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Presented by &lt;strong>Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong>. Chief Scientist, International Fertiliser Association.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Launch</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil">iSDAsoil&lt;/a> previously launched on 23&lt;sup>rd&lt;/sup> October 2020 and is an open access soil property map with 30m resolution for Africa. iSDA has collaborated with &lt;a href="https://www.worldagroforestry.org/">ICRAF&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.rothamsted.ac.uk/">Rothamsted Research&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://envirometrix.nl/">Envirometrix&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://gilab.rs/">GiLab&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://multione.hr/home.html">MultiOne&lt;/a> to gather the immense dataset which underpins this work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using on-site soil samples and computer modelling, a detailed and interactive image is produced displaying multiple properties of the soil throughout Africa. The high resolution of the data (24 billion data points) means that a single farm can identify the soil type accurate to a particular field. iSDAsoil also takes into account the depth of soil and the type of underlying bedrock to predict the full picture of soil status across the country. Where there are data gaps, iSDAsoil will be improved upon with further data received from dedicated soil agronomists.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>