<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Isdasoil on iSDA</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/isdasoil/</link><description>Recent content in Isdasoil on iSDA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.isda-africa.com/tags/isdasoil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Precision Agriculture Delivers: Coffee Farmers in Kenya Achieve 50% Yield Increase with Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/precision-agriculture-delivers-coffee-farmers-in-kenya-achieve-50-yield-increase-with-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/precision-agriculture-delivers-coffee-farmers-in-kenya-achieve-50-yield-increase-with-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee is an important cash crop to Kenya’s economy, contributing up to 10% of Kenya’s total agricultural export revenue and supporting the livelihood of more than 700,000 farmers. Poor agronomic practices, pests, diseases, low-yielding varieties and unstable market prices have contributed to low production. iSDA&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Agronomist (VA) leverages Artificial Intelligence (AI) to support smallholder farmers with farm-specific agronomic advice. Virtual Agronomist is a scientific AI tool that is delivered through a WhatsApp chatbot and advises farmers on fertiliser, pests, diseases, weather and soils. It is offered for more than 20 crops, including coffee. &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Supporting Healthy Soils for Healthy Cities: Virtual Agronomist's Role in Urban and Peri-Urban Agriculture</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/supporting-healthy-soils-for-healthy-cities-virtual-agronomists-role-in-urban-and-peri-urban-agriculture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 marks the United Nations World Soil Day (WSD). This year&amp;rsquo;s theme, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Healthy soils for healthy cities,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; highlights the critical role of soils in urban areas. Healthy urban soils filter water, store carbon, regulate temperatures, support biodiversity and even sustain food production. With two-thirds of the world&amp;rsquo;s population expected to live in cities by 2050, there is an urgent need for a one health approach across urban spaces to sustain and restore the health of our soils, the health of our cities, ecosystems and people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>200,000 Plots and Counting: Celebrating One Year of Our Virtual Agronomist AI Advisory Service</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/virtual-agronomist-one-year/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In its first year, our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt; has provided tailored nutrient recommendations for over 200,000 farm plots across Africa. This confirms our mission to empower African farmers with easy-to-access tailored, data-driven insights to enhance productivity, profitability, sustainability, and decision-making. Using our extensive knowledge base, &lt;a href="isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; soil analysis, and advisory engine, our service is designed to provide instant, personalised guidance throughout the farming season — helping farmers optimise crop health, manage resources efficiently, and navigate climate challenges with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2024 in Review: Celebrating a Year of Milestones and Impact</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2024-isda-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2024 comes to an end, our team at iSDA are proud to look back on a year marked by progress, innovation, and meaningful impact. This year has been a significant step forward in our mission to transform smallholder farming across Africa through our &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist AI advisory service&lt;/a&gt;, empowering farmers with tailored, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From expanding our reach to enhancing the accuracy of our AI-driven advice, we have seen firsthand how Virtual Agronomist can support sustainable farming practices, improve yields, and unlock potential for communities that rely on agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>10,000 Farmers: Next Generation Virtual Agronomist Launches in Kenya and Uganda</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:47:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/10000-farmers-next-generation-virtual-agronomist-launches-in-kenya-and-uganda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that our next generation &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, has amassed 10,000 users across Kenya and Uganda in less than four weeks. We are immensely proud to see such fast uptake of the work we have been doing behind the scenes and on the ground to improve the livelihoods of farmers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike our previous mobile application, our new generation of Virtual Agronomist uses artificial intelligence to communicate directly with farmers through WhatsApp and provide tailored nutrient plans and other agronomic advice for their plots. In February 2024, we launched our AI chatbot service in Kenya and Uganda for rice and maize to help farmers improve their yields and profits through better agronomic management. We wanted farmers to be able to have this vital agricultural information at their fingertips without common barriers, such as expensive land surveyor costs and lack of modern phone technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA Soil: The Backbone of Virtual Agronomist</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:29:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/isda-soil-the-backbone-of-virtual-agronomist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At iSDA, we have created the first field-level soil map for Africa, which estimates over twenty soil properties across the entire continent. These properties range from chemical factors, like aluminium and pH levels, to physical factors, such as clay content and slope angles, and soil nutrients like potassium and zinc. Our soil map at &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; stands out as the sole resource that predicts soil properties at 30 m resolution for the entire continent. This sets it apart from global soil maps, which typically offer resolutions of 250 m. Our higher spatial resolution enhances the precision of our predictions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil used in malaria mapping study</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-07-28-isdasoil-malaria-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;iSDA’s soil and agronomy map iSDAsoil was recently used by scientists to create a framework to map the malaria exposure levels of Africans living in towns and cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though iSDAsoil is primarily used by iSDA as input for Virtual Agronomist, which determines the best use and combinations of fertilisers on their land, it also contains information on different chemical and physical soil properties that were used by these scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soil pH has an effect on the habitats of the Anopheles mosquito which transmits malaria. The scientists in this study therefore incorporated soil pH data to further determine the possible habitats of the mosquitoes. For this, they used open data from iSDAsoil at a depth of 0–20 cm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sustain Africa - increasing access to affordable fertiliser at scale</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2023-06-22-sustain-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As fertiliser prices continued to spike due to the Russia/Ukraine conflict, iSDA joined the &lt;a href="https://sustainafrica-initiative.org"&gt;Sustain Africa&lt;/a&gt; initiative in 2022 to increase African farmers&amp;rsquo; access to affordable fertiliser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great challenge when it comes to fertiliser use in Africa is the lack of precision in delivering the correct chemical formulation needed for each patch of farmland. Not all soils are formed or managed equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iSDA&amp;rsquo;s role in the Sustain Africa initiative has therefore been to deploy our app &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist/"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt; to tackle this issue. The system was created to provide individual farmers in Africa, who usually do not have access to lab testing, the ability to assess the soil properties of their farmland and provide nutrient management plans for sustainable increases in crop yield.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDA exhibiting at AGRF Summit, Kigali</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 08:46:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2022-09-04-isda-at-agrf-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grow-nourish-reward---bold-actions-for-resilient-food-systems"&gt;Grow. Nourish. Reward - Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://agrf.org/AGRFSummit/"&gt;AGRF&lt;/a&gt;, Africa’s premier forum for driving the food and agriculture agenda in the continent, will host its 12th annual summit under the theme Grow. Nourish. Reward – Bold Actions for Resilient Food Systems from September 5-9, 2022 in Kigali, Rwanda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_7d726292839b79a2.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_43bdc567e031fb0b.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/img/post/agrf-partners_hu_7d726292839b79a2.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be attending and exhibiting our products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directly supporting the aims of the summit is &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/virtual-agronomist"&gt;Virtual Agronomist&lt;/a&gt;, our system for expert advisory for farmers at scale, which supports resilient food systems by improving smallholder farmer yields and incomes, and by reducing waste through individualised fertiliser plans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AfCPA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-26-afcpa-conference/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="notes-from-the-first-african-conference-on-precision-agriculture-8th-to-10th-december-2020"&gt;Notes from the first African Conference on Precision Agriculture, 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December 2020.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session was hosted by Jonathan Crouch (CEO, iSDA) with contributions from Matt Miller (Lead Data Scientist, iSDA), Jamie Collinson (CTO, iSDA), and Keith Shepherd (Head of Diagnostics and Decision Science, iSDA). The Panel comprised Praveen Singh (Agronomist, Indorama), Pieter Pypers (Senior Agronomist, International Institute of Tropical Agriculture), and Rik van den Bosch (Director, International Soil Reference and Information Centre).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>University of Aberdeen’s research project to tackle land loss in Ethiopia, utilises iSDAsoil</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-03-22-university-of-aberdeen-research-ethiopia-utilises-isdasoil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;David McBey and Michael Martin from the University of Aberdeen speak to iSDA about how they are using the iSDAsoil resource to underpin the tools developed for their project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project – &lt;a href="https://www.abdn.ac.uk/news/14502/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reducing land degradation and carbon loss from Ethiopia’s soils to strengthen livelihoods and resilience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – is funded through a £1,000,000 grant from the &lt;a href="https://www.ukri.org/our-work/collaborating-internationally/global-challenges-research-fund/"&gt;UKRI Global Challenges Research Fund (GCRF)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

&lt;img
 src="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_20c75c8eb0f69211.webp"
 srcset="https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_de0477d3aff9578f.webp 2x, https://www.isda-africa.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UoA_Primary_Logo_RGB-1024x281_hu_20c75c8eb0f69211.webp 1x"
 class="img-fluid"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="david-mcbey-describes-the-project-aims-and-background"&gt;David McBey describes the project aims and background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My background is that I’m a social scientist. I’m employed on this project as an environmental modeller. We’re most interested in Ethiopia, because there’s a lot of degraded land there. I think it is about a quarter of the land, which impacts about a third of the population.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ASA Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-18-asa-conference-10-11-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from the Special symposium on Translating Visionary Science for Excellence in African Agronomy at The American Society of Agronomy (ASA), the Crop Science Society of America (CSSA), and the Soil Science Society of America (SSSA) International Annual Meeting. 10th to 11th November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/"&gt;View the recorded videos from the conference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="african-soils-at-30-m-resolution-a-breakthrough-for-low-cost-agronomic-advisory"&gt;African soils at 30-m resolution. A breakthrough for low-cost agronomic advisory.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by &lt;strong&gt;Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt;. Chief Scientist, International Fertiliser Association.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil Launch</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-isdasoil-launch/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt; previously launched on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; October 2020 and is an open access soil property map with 30m resolution for Africa. iSDA has collaborated with &lt;a href="https://www.worldagroforestry.org/"&gt;ICRAF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.rothamsted.ac.uk/"&gt;Rothamsted Research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://envirometrix.nl/"&gt;Envirometrix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gilab.rs/"&gt;GiLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://multione.hr/home.html"&gt;MultiOne&lt;/a&gt; to gather the immense dataset which underpins this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using on-site soil samples and computer modelling, a detailed and interactive image is produced displaying multiple properties of the soil throughout Africa. The high resolution of the data (24 billion data points) means that a single farm can identify the soil type accurate to a particular field. iSDAsoil also takes into account the depth of soil and the type of underlying bedrock to predict the full picture of soil status across the country. Where there are data gaps, iSDAsoil will be improved upon with further data received from dedicated soil agronomists.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>International Fertilizer Association Webinar 26 February 2021</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-02-16-international-fertilizer-association-webinar-26-february-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-information-revolution-in-africa-introducing-isdasoil"&gt;An information revolution in Africa? Introducing iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="26-february-2021-3pm-to-4pm-cet"&gt;26 February 2021, 3pm to 4pm CET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFA, the International Fertilizer Association is holding a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_UwuVtU-VTziZIJ1MTUtQlg"&gt;free webinar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focusing on &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;. IFA’s Members include fertilizer producers, traders and distributors, as well as their associations, service providers to the industry, research organizations, and non-governmental organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for a live demonstration of iSDAsoil with the team, and a discussion with &lt;strong&gt;IFA Chief Scientist Achim Dobermann&lt;/strong&gt; on what this mapping can mean for the future of farming in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the AfCPA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2021-01-11-isdasoil-at-the-afcpa-virtual-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, the iSDA team made two presentations at The 1st African Conference on Precision Agriculture (AfCPA) in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="an-introduction-to-isdasoil"&gt;An introduction to iSDAsoil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Crouch, CEO of iSDA presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the history of digital soil mapping in Africa, the improvements made in iSDAsoil, and some applications of the resource:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MgX3tmDtbps?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-isdasoil-interactive-workshop"&gt;The iSDAsoil interactive workshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iSDA team then held an in-depth interactive session on iSDAsoil. This consisted of a live demo of iSDAsoil’s functionality, an expert panel discussion, and Q&amp;amp;A. The panel discussion members were:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>iSDAsoil at the ASA-CSSA-SSSA Virtual Conference</title><link>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.isda-africa.com/posts/2020-12-03-isdasoil-asa-cssa-sssa-virtual-conference-recording/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.isda-africa.com/isdasoil/"&gt;iSDAsoil&lt;/a&gt;, the iSDA team made two presentations at The American Society of Agronomy, the Crop Science Society of America, and the Soil Science Society of America (ASA-CSSA-SSSA) Conference. This international virtual conference ran from the 9-13 November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achim Dobermann of the iSDA Board presented an overview of iSDAsoil. He outlined the problem space, importance of the breakthrough, and its potential applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EWbosAsGvGE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Achim Dobermann presents iSDAsoil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>